<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>FlowForge</title>
    <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self"/>
    <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog"/>
    <updated>2023-01-12T12:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://flowforge.com/blog</id>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2023/01/flowforge-1.2.1-released/</id>
        <title>FlowForge 1.2.1 released</title>
        <summary>Release includes fix for emailing new user</summary>
        <updated>2023-01-12T12:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2023/01/flowforge-1.2.1-released/"/>
        <author><name>Ben Hardill</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve published a maintenance release containing a fix for new users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release fixes an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/1537&quot;&gt;issue&lt;/a&gt; introduced in FlowForge 1.2 where users were not being sent their welcome email when they first sign up to the platform. As the sign-up page asks them to click on the link in that email, it left them waiting for an email that wasn&#39;t going to arrive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same fix also addresses an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/1514&quot;&gt;issue&lt;/a&gt; where users could not sign up using an email with a &lt;code&gt;+&lt;/code&gt; in it. This is a restriction we apply to users signing up with Single Sign-On enabled email domains - but the check was being applied to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;upgrading-flowforge&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2023/01/flowforge-1.2.1-released/#upgrading-flowforge&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Upgrading FlowForge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release has already been rolled out to &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.flowforge.com/&quot;&gt;FlowForge Cloud&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you installed a previous version of FlowForge and want to upgrade, our documentation provides a
guide for &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/install/upgrading/&quot;&gt;upgrading your FlowForge instance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-help&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2023/01/flowforge-1.2.1-released/#getting-help&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Getting help&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please check FlowForge&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; as the answers to many questions are covered there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you hit any problems with the platform, please raise an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues&quot;&gt;issue on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.
That also includes if you have any feedback or feature requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chat with us on the &lt;code&gt;#flowforge&lt;/code&gt; channel on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodered.org/slack&quot;&gt;Node-RED Slack workspace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also raise a support ticket by emailing &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@flowforge.com&quot;&gt;support@flowforge.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/flowforge-1-2-0-released/</id>
        <title>FlowForge 1.2 is now available with single sign on and persistent context storage</title>
        <summary>Our final release for 2022 with some great new features to try out</summary>
        <updated>2022-12-22T18:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/flowforge-1-2-0-released/"/>
        <author><name>Rob Marcer</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Control access to FlowForge using single sign-on and retain context values when restarting projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re pleased to announce version 1.2 is now available! The latest release of the FlowForge application contains new features, improvements, better documentation, and bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve put a great deal of work in this release to make it easier to run your own self-managed instance of FlowForge. That includes significant improvements for FlowForge in &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/install/kubernetes/&quot;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/install/docker/&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep reading for the details of what&#39;s in this release or you can watch our 1 minute roundup video of the new release above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;features&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/flowforge-1-2-0-released/#features&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/226&quot;&gt;Single Sign-On&lt;/a&gt; Single sign-on (SSO) is a method of authentication that allows a user to access multiple applications or systems with a single set of login credentials, improving security, productivity, and user experience, and reducing IT overhead. We&#39;ve implemented SSO using the Security Assertion Markup Language &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Security_Assertion_Markup_Language&quot;&gt;(SAML)&lt;/a&gt; framework. This allows users of FlowForge Cloud, Premium and the open source edition to easily access their FlowForge projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/212&quot;&gt;Persistent Context&lt;/a&gt; Node-RED provides a way to store information that can be shared between different nodes and flow executions without using the messages that pass through a flow. This is called ‘context’. You can now select if context should be stored in memory or in persistent storage. Persistent storage allows the stored values to be recalled after a restart of your project. You can see a demonstration of this feature on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/ma2vYrXmssc&quot;&gt;Youtube channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;improvements&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/flowforge-1-2-0-released/#improvements&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In FlowForge 1.1 we added logging of user actions. In 1.2 we’ve &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/517&quot;&gt;improved the audit log interface&lt;/a&gt; to help you read the recorded user actions.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/images/audit-log.png&quot; alt=&quot;An image of the new audit log interface&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Configuring DNS for FlowForge has historically been challenging as for most FlowForge installs you&#39;ll need two entries. One for the FlowForge application, and one for the Node-RED projects. There&#39;s been updates to the documentation to make it much easier to set this up, and much faster. Please checkout the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/install/dns-setup/&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve updated our documentation to always link to the latest build (older builds are still available).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously customers were asked to build their own containers for the main FlowForge applications, as well as the Node-RED ones. For the Node-RED containers this allows customers to pre-install packages in the container they intent to use. For FlowForge Cloud these containers are build by FlowForge. These containers are now published to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hub.docker.com/u/flowforge&quot;&gt;Docker Hub&lt;/a&gt;. This makes it much easier to get up and running with your first containers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are now pushing our Docker builds to Docker Hub, this saves users from having to build the Docker images when installing or updating. These containers are used by default by &lt;code&gt;docker-compose&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Setting up MQTT for inter-project communication and communication with devices has been simplified. Please read the improved the documentation around configuration of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/1397&quot;&gt;MQTT&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;bug-fixes&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/flowforge-1-2-0-released/#bug-fixes&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Bug Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve fixed the following bugs in this release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unable to edit &#39;Prevent Install of External nodes&#39; template option &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/1376&quot;&gt;#1376&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Self-managed FlowForge needs an external email server to deliver email to users. FlowForge should be able deal with the email server being offline and gracefully recover once it is back online. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/1159&quot;&gt;#1159&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Duplicate Activity Log for Project whose state is in flight &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/1461&quot;&gt;#1461&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;contributors-todo&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/flowforge-1-2-0-released/#contributors-todo&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Contributors TODO&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;d like the thank the following for their contributions to this release:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flecoufle&quot;&gt;flecoufle&lt;/a&gt; for their work on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/docker-compose/pull/59&quot;&gt;#59&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sumanpaikdev&quot;&gt;sumanpaikdev&lt;/a&gt; for their work on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/docker-compose/pull/53&quot;&gt;#53&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sdirosa&quot;&gt;sdirosa&lt;/a&gt; for their work on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/pull/1326&quot;&gt;#1326&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an open-source project, we welcome community involvement in what we&#39;re building.
If you&#39;re interested in contributing, checkout our &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/contribute/&quot;&gt;guide in the docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;try-it-out&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/flowforge-1-2-0-released/#try-it-out&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Try it out&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1.2 we&#39;ve continued to improve the experience of running your own self managed FlowForge installation. We&#39;re confident you can have self managed FlowForge running locally in under 30 minutes.
You can install our &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/install/local/&quot;&gt;local build&lt;/a&gt;, through &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/install/docker/&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/install/kubernetes/&quot;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;d rather use our hosted offering: &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.flowforge.com/account/create?code=FF12&quot;&gt;Sign up for FlowForge Cloud&lt;/a&gt;
with the coupon &lt;strong&gt;FF12&lt;/strong&gt; to get your first project free for a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;upgrading-flowforge&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/flowforge-1-2-0-released/#upgrading-flowforge&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Upgrading FlowForge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://app.flowforge.com/&quot;&gt;FlowForge Cloud&lt;/a&gt; is already running 1.2. To use
persistent context you&#39;ll need to upgrade your projects stack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you installed a previous version of FlowForge and want to upgrade, our documentation provides a
guide for &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/upgrade/&quot;&gt;upgrading your FlowForge instance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-help&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/flowforge-1-2-0-released/#getting-help&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Getting help&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please check FlowForge&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; as the answers to many questions are covered there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you hit any problems with the platform please raise an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues&quot;&gt;issue on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.
That also includes if you have any feedback or feature requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chat with us on the &lt;code&gt;#flowforge&lt;/code&gt; channel on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodered.org/slack&quot;&gt;Node-RED Slack workspace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can raise a support ticket by emailing &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@flowforge.com&quot;&gt;support@flowforge.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve also added a live chat widget to our website, you can access it using the icon on the bottom right corner of our website. We&#39;d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/what-flowforge-adds-to-node-red/</id>
        <title>Why you need FlowForge when you already have Node-RED?</title>
        <summary>FlowForge makes developer collaboration, flow deployment, and scaling of infrastructure easy when working with Node-RED</summary>
        <updated>2022-12-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/what-flowforge-adds-to-node-red/"/>
        <author><name>Rob Marcer</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Many organisations face challenges in IT/OT convergence. There are many protocols, disparate devices, and everything is a brownfield project. Furthermore, skilled engineers are hard to find. Many organisations find themselves maintaining systems and integrations, and have little time left to improve continuously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why Node-RED is adopted so widely, it makes a world of difference through two of its properties: Low-Code Development and the ability to integrate with a wide range of hardware and software systems. Node-RED makes it easy to program data collection, then use that data for decision making, and provide feedback to both your digital platform and the physical reality of your business. Furthermore, Node-RED is unrivalled in making data accessible. The data previously locked in a walled garden of your hardware providers is now accessible and obtainable. With that, more data is available and better decisions are made, faster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FlowForge makes developer collaboration, flow deployment, and scaling of infrastructure easy when working with Node-RED. It offers an intuitive user interface for creating, deploying, monitoring, and managing multiple Node-RED projects. FlowForge also provides one-click deployment to thousands of devices, making it easy to manage large-scale environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These features make FlowForge a valuable tool for organisations using Node-RED to build applications and automate processes. Enabling for further adoption of Node-RED to integrate more systems, for even better decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This not only reduces operational costs but it also allows an organisation to be far more agile with their Node-RED projects than was possible without FlowForge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would be happy to talk to you more about how FlowForge can help you get the most value from Node-RED. Please &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/contact-us/&quot;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt; to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/flowforge-joins-openjs-foundation/</id>
        <title>FlowForge Inc. becomes a member of the OpenJS Foundation</title>
        <summary>Supporting the foundation that has given Node-RED a great home</summary>
        <updated>2022-12-13T12:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/flowforge-joins-openjs-foundation/"/>
        <author><name>Nick O&#39;Leary</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re pleased to share the news we&#39;ve joined the OpenJS Foundation to bolster our
support for the Node-RED community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/handbook/company/#open-source-stewardship&quot;&gt;founding principles&lt;/a&gt; is
the importance of Open Source being at the core of what we do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Node-RED has been part of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://openjsf.org/&quot;&gt;OpenJS Foundation&lt;/a&gt; since it was formed in 2019.
The Foundation provides the project a vendor-neutral home and enables its open governance model that
allows anyone to get involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also provides some vitally important resources to the community, such as the hosting for the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://discourse.nodered.org/&quot;&gt;community forum&lt;/a&gt;, which regularly gets over 1.5 Million page views a
month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With my Node-RED Project Lead hat on, I regularly see the impact the foundation has had on the growth
of the Node-RED community. These are things that may not always be obvious to our end users, but
we wouldn&#39;t be where we are today with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The success of what we&#39;re building with FlowForge relies on a strong and healthy Node-RED community.
Becoming members of the Foundation allows us to provide more yet more support to Node-RED and the wider
JavaScript communities represented by the foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information about this news, check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://openjsf.org/announcement/2022/12/13/welcoming-flowforge-to-the-openjs-foundation/&quot;&gt;OpenJS Foundation blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/node-red-exec-explained/</id>
        <title>Node-RED Exec nodes explained</title>
        <summary>Node-RED by default comes with the Exec node. This node allows you to run a command as if you&#39;re on the command line. In this article we discuss how that can be useful and why exec is not included in FlowForge.</summary>
        <updated>2022-12-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/node-red-exec-explained/"/>
        <author><name>ZJ van de Weg</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Node-RED is written in Javascript, as are the custom nodes in the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://flows.nodered.org/search?type=node&quot;&gt;Flows Library&lt;/a&gt;. At times it would
be great to use programs written in other languages. In this guide we&#39;ll explain
the &lt;code&gt;exec&lt;/code&gt; node.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;exec-node&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/node-red-exec-explained/#exec-node&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Exec Node&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Node-RED by default comes with the &lt;code&gt;exec&lt;/code&gt; node. This node allows you to run a
command as if you&#39;re on the command line. The exec node has one input, and three
outputs. Let&#39;s create a basic example and work from there. Let&#39;s connect the
inject to the &lt;code&gt;exec&lt;/code&gt; input, and connect the three dots to debug nodes. I&#39;ve set
the command in the exec node to &lt;code&gt;date&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/images/wired-up-exec-node.png&quot; alt=&quot;&amp;quot;Wired up exec node&amp;quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When triggered, you&#39;ll see two outputs in the debug pane. One from &lt;code&gt;Standard out&lt;/code&gt;;
the date and timestamp of the execution and the &lt;code&gt;Exit code&lt;/code&gt; will output too.
&lt;code&gt;Standard error&lt;/code&gt; didn&#39;t output anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s explain what happened: the &lt;code&gt;date&lt;/code&gt; command was executed by the NodeJS without
any input. The command returned the date as a string, and execution of the commmand
completed. There weren&#39;t any errors, so the error code is set to zero. Non-zero
exit codes imply didn&#39;t go as intended. Output is written to the standard output,
and not standard error. This allows us to handle errors differently from succesful
exections and the output in standard output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;exec-vs-spawn-mode&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/node-red-exec-explained/#exec-vs-spawn-mode&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Exec vs Spawn mode&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s change the &lt;code&gt;exec&lt;/code&gt; node to execute &lt;code&gt;ping google.com&lt;/code&gt;. The ping command
provides the round-trip time to google.com in milliseconds, each second. When
we deploy, the program is stuck. That&#39;s because the output is generated each
second and won&#39;t complete until there&#39;s a failure in the command. Not what you&#39;d
want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When there&#39;s continous output you&#39;ll need to select &lt;code&gt;spawn&lt;/code&gt; mode in the settings
windown of the &lt;code&gt;exec&lt;/code&gt; node:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/images/spawn-mode-exec.png&quot; alt=&quot;spawn mode for exec in Node-RED&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will produce a message per line to the standard out output for further
processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;flowforge&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/node-red-exec-explained/#flowforge&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; FlowForge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On FlowForge Cloud, the Node-RED exec nodes are disabled. The Stacks, that is the
containers that Node-RED runs in, don&#39;t include any accessible executatables so there would be no benefit to running exec commands. All the data is exposed through Javascript and Node.JS already.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/flowforge-1-1-2-released/</id>
        <title>FlowForge 1.1.2 released</title>
        <summary>Release includes a fix for installing additional nodes into Node-RED.</summary>
        <updated>2022-12-09T12:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/flowforge-1-1-2-released/"/>
        <author><name>Nick O&#39;Leary</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve published a maintenance fix with an important fix for the Palette Manager in Node-RED.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/1367&quot;&gt;bug&lt;/a&gt; was reported this week
where a user was unable to install additional nodes into their Node-RED project
using the editor&#39;s palette manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tracked it down to an issue that was introduced in the 1.1 release, where the
project template lets you list nodes that should be blocked from being installed.
It was interpreting an empty list to mean &lt;em&gt;disallow everything&lt;/em&gt;! Not quite the
intended behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst tracking this down, we also spotted a bug (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/1379&quot;&gt;#1379&lt;/a&gt;)
around editing this same setting that made it tricky to work around without this
release being published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These issues have now been fixed and FlowForge 1.1.2 published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;bug-fixes&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/flowforge-1-1-2-released/#bug-fixes&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Bug Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In additional to the above issues, this release includes some further fixes around
the docker and helm components:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix fileStore hostname by @flecoufle in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/docker-compose/pull/59&quot;&gt;#59&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix healthcheck &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/docker-compose/pull/62&quot;&gt;#62&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/docker-compose/pull/63&quot;&gt;#63&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/helm/pull/74&quot;&gt;#74&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;contributors&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/flowforge-1-1-2-released/#contributors&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Contributors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;d like to thank the following people for their contributions to this release:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flecoufle&quot;&gt;flecoufle&lt;/a&gt; for their work on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/docker-compose/pull/59&quot;&gt;#59&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an open-source project, we welcome community involvement in what we&#39;re building.
If you&#39;re interested in contributing, checkout our &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/contribute/&quot;&gt;guide in the docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;upgrading-flowforge&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/flowforge-1-1-2-released/#upgrading-flowforge&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Upgrading FlowForge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release has already been rolled out to &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.flowforge.com/&quot;&gt;FlowForge Cloud&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you installed a previous version of FlowForge and want to upgrade, our documentation provides a
guide for &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/install/upgrading/&quot;&gt;upgrading your FlowForge instance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-help&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/flowforge-1-1-2-released/#getting-help&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Getting help&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please check FlowForge&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; as the answers to many questions are covered there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you hit any problems with the platform, please raise an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues&quot;&gt;issue on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.
That also includes if you have any feedback or feature requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chat with us on the &lt;code&gt;#flowforge&lt;/code&gt; channel on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodered.org/slack&quot;&gt;Node-RED Slack workspace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also raise a support ticket by emailing &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@flowforge.com&quot;&gt;support@flowforge.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/flowforge-gcp-https-set-up/</id>
        <title>Configure FlowForge in Docker to secure all traffic</title>
        <summary>Use Let&#39;s Encrypt and Acme Companion to quickly set up FlowForge to encrypt all traffic</summary>
        <updated>2022-12-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/flowforge-gcp-https-set-up/"/>
        <author><name>Rob Marcer</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Following on from our &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/ff-docker-gcp/&quot;&gt;previous article&lt;/a&gt; in which we covered how to run FlowForge in Docker on Google’s Cloud Platform, today we are going to look at how to secure HTTP traffic to your FlowForge server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;introduction&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/flowforge-gcp-https-set-up/#introduction&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we wrote the first part of this series FlowForge didn&#39;t have an easy path to secure HTTP traffic. Happily, two versions of FlowForge later and at least partially inspired by these blogs, we have added the configuration you need in Docker to use HTTPS with minimal work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That addition makes our job of explaining this setup a lot easier, credit to our developers for seeing the value of having an easy implementation of HTTPS in FlowForge as part of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/flowforge-1-released/&quot;&gt;1.0 build&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To achieve secure HTTPS traffic we are employing a great service called &lt;a href=&quot;https://letsencrypt.org/&quot;&gt;Let&#39;s Encrypt&lt;/a&gt;. In their own words, &amp;quot;Let’s Encrypt is a free, automated, and open certificate authority (CA), run for the public’s benefit&amp;quot;. In practice Let&#39;s Encrypt will allow us to easily secure HTTPS traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are also utilising a Docker image called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nginx-proxy/acme-companion&quot;&gt;acme-companion&lt;/a&gt; which makes the configuration of Let&#39;s Encrypt a breeze. To quote the project&#39;s own Github page &amp;quot;acme-companion is a lightweight companion container for nginx-proxy. It handles the automated creation, renewal and use of SSL certificates for proxied Docker containers through the ACME protocol&amp;quot;. It&#39;s a great project and credit to the team over there for making it a lot easier to secure the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we&#39;ve covered our goals and the tools we are going to use let&#39;s configure our existing GCP VM to secure all web traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;prerequisites&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/flowforge-gcp-https-set-up/#prerequisites&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Prerequisites&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, you will need to be running FlowForge version 1.0 or higher to follow this guide. If you are using an older version you can upgrade now using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/install/upgrading/&quot;&gt;instructions here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;update-docker-compose&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/flowforge-gcp-https-set-up/#update-docker-compose&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Update Docker Compose&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step is to edit our Docker compose file. We&#39;re using Nano again to edit files so we will run this command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo nano /opt/flowforge/docker-compose-1.1.1/docker-compose.yml
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the docker-compose.yml file, un-comment the following lines:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;position: relative&quot;&gt;
  &lt;pre class=&quot;language-yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;code id=&quot;code-38&quot; class=&quot;language-yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;./certs:/etc/nginx/certs&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

  &lt;button class=&quot;code-copy &quot; data-clipboard-target=&quot;#code-38&quot; style=&quot;position: absolute; top: 7.5px; right: 6px; cursor: pointer; outline: none; opacity: 0.8;&quot; title=&quot;Copy&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;
      &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 15px; opacity: 0.8;&quot; class=&quot;mdi mdi-content-copy&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;position: relative&quot;&gt;
  &lt;pre class=&quot;language-yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;code id=&quot;code-39&quot; class=&quot;language-yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;443:443&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

  &lt;button class=&quot;code-copy &quot; data-clipboard-target=&quot;#code-39&quot; style=&quot;position: absolute; top: 7.5px; right: 6px; cursor: pointer; outline: none; opacity: 0.8;&quot; title=&quot;Copy&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;
      &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 15px; opacity: 0.8;&quot; class=&quot;mdi mdi-content-copy&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;position: relative&quot;&gt;
  &lt;pre class=&quot;language-yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;code id=&quot;code-40&quot; class=&quot;language-yaml&quot;&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token key atrule&quot;&gt;acme&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token key atrule&quot;&gt;image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; nginxproxy/acme&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;companion&lt;br /&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token key atrule&quot;&gt;volumes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;      &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;/var/run/docker.sock:/var/run/docker.sock:ro&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;      &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;./acme:/etc/acme.sh&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token key atrule&quot;&gt;volumes_from&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;      &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; nginx&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;rw&lt;br /&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token key atrule&quot;&gt;environment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;      &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;DEFAULT_EMAIL=mail@example.com&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;token key atrule&quot;&gt;depends_on&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;      &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;nginx&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

  &lt;button class=&quot;code-copy &quot; data-clipboard-target=&quot;#code-40&quot; style=&quot;position: absolute; top: 7.5px; right: 6px; cursor: pointer; outline: none; opacity: 0.8;&quot; title=&quot;Copy&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;
      &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 15px; opacity: 0.8;&quot; class=&quot;mdi mdi-content-copy&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should also redirect all traffic to use HTTPS, to do that un-comment the following in the nginx service section:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;position: relative&quot;&gt;
  &lt;pre class=&quot;language-yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;code id=&quot;code-44&quot; class=&quot;language-yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token key atrule&quot;&gt;Environment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;      &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;HTTPS_METHOD=redirect&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

  &lt;button class=&quot;code-copy &quot; data-clipboard-target=&quot;#code-44&quot; style=&quot;position: absolute; top: 7.5px; right: 6px; cursor: pointer; outline: none; opacity: 0.8;&quot; title=&quot;Copy&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;
      &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 15px; opacity: 0.8;&quot; class=&quot;mdi mdi-content-copy&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We now need to add the configuration for LetsEncrypt, edit the following lines to include a valid email address and the correct domain for where you are hosting your FlowForge server:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;position: relative&quot;&gt;
  &lt;pre class=&quot;language-yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;code id=&quot;code-48&quot; class=&quot;language-yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;DEFAULT_EMAIL=mail@example.com&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

  &lt;button class=&quot;code-copy &quot; data-clipboard-target=&quot;#code-48&quot; style=&quot;position: absolute; top: 7.5px; right: 6px; cursor: pointer; outline: none; opacity: 0.8;&quot; title=&quot;Copy&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;
      &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 15px; opacity: 0.8;&quot; class=&quot;mdi mdi-content-copy&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;position: relative&quot;&gt;
  &lt;pre class=&quot;language-yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;code id=&quot;code-49&quot; class=&quot;language-yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;LETSENCRYPT_HOST=mqtt.example.com&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

  &lt;button class=&quot;code-copy &quot; data-clipboard-target=&quot;#code-49&quot; style=&quot;position: absolute; top: 7.5px; right: 6px; cursor: pointer; outline: none; opacity: 0.8;&quot; title=&quot;Copy&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;
      &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 15px; opacity: 0.8;&quot; class=&quot;mdi mdi-content-copy&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;position: relative&quot;&gt;
  &lt;pre class=&quot;language-yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;code id=&quot;code-50&quot; class=&quot;language-yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;LETSENCRYPT_HOST=forge.example.com&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

  &lt;button class=&quot;code-copy &quot; data-clipboard-target=&quot;#code-50&quot; style=&quot;position: absolute; top: 7.5px; right: 6px; cursor: pointer; outline: none; opacity: 0.8;&quot; title=&quot;Copy&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;
      &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 15px; opacity: 0.8;&quot; class=&quot;mdi mdi-content-copy&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save and exit from that file, in Nano you can do that by pressing ‘control x’ then ‘y’ then the Return key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;update-flowforge.yml&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/flowforge-gcp-https-set-up/#update-flowforge.yml&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Update flowforge.yml&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, we need to edit the public_url for the MQTT broker:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo nano /opt/flowforge/docker-compose-1.1.1/docker-compose.yml
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then replace ws:// with wss://&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;position: relative&quot;&gt;
  &lt;pre class=&quot;language-yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;code id=&quot;code-64&quot; class=&quot;language-yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token key atrule&quot;&gt;public_url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; wss&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;//mqtt.flowforge&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;demo.com&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

  &lt;button class=&quot;code-copy &quot; data-clipboard-target=&quot;#code-64&quot; style=&quot;position: absolute; top: 7.5px; right: 6px; cursor: pointer; outline: none; opacity: 0.8;&quot; title=&quot;Copy&quot;&gt;
    &lt;span&gt;
      &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 15px; opacity: 0.8;&quot; class=&quot;mdi mdi-content-copy&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;/button&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save and exit from that file, in Nano you can do that by pressing ‘control x’ then ‘y’ then the Return key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;restart-your-docker-containers&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/flowforge-gcp-https-set-up/#restart-your-docker-containers&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Restart your Docker containers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OK, we should be ready to restart the Docker containers, run the command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo docker compose -p flowforge up -d
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you reload your FlowForge root directory in a web browser you should now see that your traffic is encrypted using LetsEncypt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/images/https-working.png&quot; alt=&quot;A screenshot from Safari web browser showing that the traffic to FlowForge is encrypted&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nice! That’s it, you can now access your FlowForge installation securely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next and final part of this series of articles, we are going to look at how we can actually use FlowForge including how to build flows and deploy and update them on Devices linked to a project.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/Create-http-trigger-with-authentication/</id>
        <title>Create HTTP triggers with authentication</title>
        <summary>From any browser or command line you now have the ability to securely trigger your flows</summary>
        <updated>2022-12-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/Create-http-trigger-with-authentication/"/>
        <author><name>Rob Marcer</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Having an HTTP endpoint trigger your flows is very useful. From any browser or command line you now have the ability to trigger your flows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing so safely with authentication is slightly harder, but not a lot. FlowForge makes it rather easy to accomplish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;creating-the-http-flow&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/Create-http-trigger-with-authentication/#creating-the-http-flow&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Creating the HTTP flow&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you start a project on FlowForge, remember the project name. For this how-to we’ll use &lt;code&gt;example&lt;/code&gt;. Open the editor and drag in the HTTP In node as well as the HTTP response node. Connect them, and add a debug node, which is connected to the “HTTP in” node.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off; let’s set the HTTP in node properties:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/images/edit-http-node.png&quot; alt=&quot;Shows the UI to edit the node&#39;s properties&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can import this flow into your own project if you’d like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[{&amp;quot;id&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;4faa84d37a52bb28&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;group&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;z&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;3c6e2dc732ada815&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;name&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Allow HTTP Post request to trigger a flow&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;style&amp;quot;:{&amp;quot;label&amp;quot;:!0},&amp;quot;nodes&amp;quot;:[&amp;quot;1fa26e0ed3ddec1a&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;45a180052e1a2f43&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;09347881f4fa4057&amp;quot;],&amp;quot;x&amp;quot;:34,&amp;quot;y&amp;quot;:79,&amp;quot;w&amp;quot;:472,&amp;quot;h&amp;quot;:122},{&amp;quot;id&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;1fa26e0ed3ddec1a&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http in&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;z&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;3c6e2dc732ada815&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;g&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;4faa84d37a52bb28&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;name&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;HTTP Trigger&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;url&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;/http-trigger&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;method&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;post&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;upload&amp;quot;:!1,&amp;quot;swaggerDoc&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;x&amp;quot;:130,&amp;quot;y&amp;quot;:120,&amp;quot;wires&amp;quot;:[[&amp;quot;45a180052e1a2f43&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;09347881f4fa4057&amp;quot;]]},{&amp;quot;id&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;45a180052e1a2f43&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http response&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;z&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;3c6e2dc732ada815&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;g&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;4faa84d37a52bb28&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;name&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Empty HTTP response&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;statusCode&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;200&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;headers&amp;quot;:{},&amp;quot;x&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;y&amp;quot;:120,&amp;quot;wires&amp;quot;:[]},{&amp;quot;id&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;09347881f4fa4057&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;type&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;debug&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;z&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;3c6e2dc732ada815&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;g&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;4faa84d37a52bb28&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;name&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Print HTTP Request&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;active&amp;quot;:!0,&amp;quot;tosidebar&amp;quot;:!0,&amp;quot;console&amp;quot;:!1,&amp;quot;tostatus&amp;quot;:!1,&amp;quot;complete&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;payload&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;targetType&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;msg&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;statusVal&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;statusType&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;auto&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;x&amp;quot;:360,&amp;quot;y&amp;quot;:160,&amp;quot;wires&amp;quot;:[]}]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I’ve opened a terminal and executed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl -X POST https://example.flowforge.com/http-trigger
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When there’s no output, that means it’s all good! There should be an empty message in the debug console in the Node-RED editor though&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;securing-the-http-trigger-with-a-username-and-password&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/Create-http-trigger-with-authentication/#securing-the-http-trigger-with-a-username-and-password&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Securing the HTTP trigger with a username and password&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with our trigger is that anyone with internet access could trigger it. That’s not a great idea. So let’s secure this endpoint with HTTP Basic Authentication. There are various ways to include a secure endpoint in Node-RED, we’ve built authentication directly into FlowForge to make it easier for all users. On the FlowForge project, go to settings and then to ‘Editor’. Under the section HTTP Auth you can set a username and password. You should generate both by a random string generator, and store the credentials somewhere safe.  Restart the project to have the runtime pick up the changes, and the endpoint is secured!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s validate the endpoint that worked a minute ago doesn’t anymore:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl -X POST https://example.flowforge.cloud/http-trigger
=&amp;gt; Unauthorized
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s get it working again: (replace &lt;username&gt; and &lt;password&gt; with the details from the sticky note)&lt;/password&gt;&lt;/username&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl -X POST https://&amp;lt;username&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;password&amp;gt;@example.flowforge.cloud/http-trigger
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s it! You now have a flow that’s protected by a username and password combination!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/node-red-flow-best-practice/</id>
        <title>Format your Node-RED flows for better team collaboration</title>
        <summary>From formatting your flows for readability to providing clear comments on nodes and groups, a little bit of effort upfront can save your team a lot of headaches down the road</summary>
        <updated>2022-12-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/node-red-flow-best-practice/"/>
        <author><name>Rob Marcer</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When it comes to working on Node-RED flows as part of a team, there are a few best practices that can make things go more smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From formatting your flows for readability to providing clear comments on nodes and groups, a little bit of effort upfront can save your team a lot of headaches down the road. In this post, we&#39;ll cover some of the main things to keep in mind when working on Node-RED flows as part of a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;give-your-groups-descriptive-names&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/node-red-flow-best-practice/#give-your-groups-descriptive-names&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Give your groups descriptive names&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodered.org/docs/user-guide/editor/workspace/groups&quot;&gt;grouping your flows&lt;/a&gt; and giving each group a clear explanation of what it does. Compare the first to the second example below and consider how much more quickly you can understand what the flow is doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;this-is-not-helpful%2C-&#39;time&#39;-doesn&#39;t-tell-you-enough-to-understand-the-flow&#39;s-purpose.&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/node-red-flow-best-practice/#this-is-not-helpful%2C-&#39;time&#39;-doesn&#39;t-tell-you-enough-to-understand-the-flow&#39;s-purpose.&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; This is not helpful, &#39;Time&#39; doesn&#39;t tell you enough to understand the flow&#39;s purpose.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/images/name-bad.png&quot; alt=&quot;This is not helpful, &#39;Time&#39; doesn&#39;t tell you enough to understand the flow&#39;s purpose.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;this-is-much-better%2C-we-know-what-the-flow-is-doing-without-inspecting-the-nodes.&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/node-red-flow-best-practice/#this-is-much-better%2C-we-know-what-the-flow-is-doing-without-inspecting-the-nodes.&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; This is much better, we know what the flow is doing without inspecting the nodes.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/images/name-good.png&quot; alt=&quot;This is much better, we know what the flow is doing without inspecting the nodes.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;explain-what-your-switches-do&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/node-red-flow-best-practice/#explain-what-your-switches-do&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Explain what your switches do&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try to make it obvious what each switch does without having to open the node editor. Ask a question in the switch&#39;s name and make a positive answer the top connection out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;this-is-not-easy-to-understand%2C-what-does-the-switch-do%3F&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/node-red-flow-best-practice/#this-is-not-easy-to-understand%2C-what-does-the-switch-do%3F&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; This is not easy to understand, what does the switch do?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/images/switch-bad.png&quot; alt=&quot;This is not easy to understand, what does the switch do?&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;this-is-a-lot-better%2C-we-can-see-that-the-top-debug-should-be-triggered.&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/node-red-flow-best-practice/#this-is-a-lot-better%2C-we-can-see-that-the-top-debug-should-be-triggered.&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; This is a lot better, we can see that the top debug should be triggered.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/images/switch-good.png&quot; alt=&quot;This is a lot better, we can see that the top debug should be triggered.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-possible-your-flows-should-work-down-the-canvas&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/node-red-flow-best-practice/#where-possible-your-flows-should-work-down-the-canvas&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Where possible your flows should work down the canvas&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It makes it so much easier to understand what happens and in which order if your flows start at the top of the canvas and work down to the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;this-is-almost-unreadable%2C-it&#39;s-very-hard-to-work-out-the-order-of-the-groups.&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/node-red-flow-best-practice/#this-is-almost-unreadable%2C-it&#39;s-very-hard-to-work-out-the-order-of-the-groups.&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; This is almost unreadable, it&#39;s very hard to work out the order of the groups.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/images/flowdown-bad.png&quot; alt=&quot;This is almost unreadable, it&#39;s very hard to work out the order of the groups.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;where-as-this-is-so-much-easier-to-understand.&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/node-red-flow-best-practice/#where-as-this-is-so-much-easier-to-understand.&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Where as this is so much easier to understand.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/images/flowdown-good.png&quot; alt=&quot;Where as this is so much easier to understand.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-link-nodes-rather-than-wires-to-join-groups&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/node-red-flow-best-practice/#use-link-nodes-rather-than-wires-to-join-groups&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Use link nodes rather than wires to join groups&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Groups should not be joined using wires, it just looks untidy and quickly reduces readability of your flows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-wire-is-blocking-the-title%2C-it-only-gets-worse-as-you-add-more-wires.&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/node-red-flow-best-practice/#the-wire-is-blocking-the-title%2C-it-only-gets-worse-as-you-add-more-wires.&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; The wire is blocking the title, it only gets worse as you add more wires.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/images/link-bad.png&quot; alt=&quot;The wire is blocking the title, it only gets worse as you add more wires.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;you-can-see-the-group-titles-easily-now.&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/node-red-flow-best-practice/#you-can-see-the-group-titles-easily-now.&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; You can see the group titles easily now.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/images/link-good.png&quot; alt=&quot;You can see the group titles easily now.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;keep-your-groups-compact&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/node-red-flow-best-practice/#keep-your-groups-compact&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Keep your groups compact&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping your groups compact will save time when reading the flow. This is especially helpful if when viewed on a smaller screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;consider-how-hard-a-flow-made-of-groups-spaced-out-like-this-would-be-to-read-on-a-smaller-laptop-screen.&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/node-red-flow-best-practice/#consider-how-hard-a-flow-made-of-groups-spaced-out-like-this-would-be-to-read-on-a-smaller-laptop-screen.&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Consider how hard a flow made of groups spaced out like this would be to read on a smaller laptop screen.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/images/compact-bad.png&quot; alt=&quot;Consider how hard a flow made of groups spaced out like this would be to read on a smaller laptop screen.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;this-now-takes-up-less-space-and-is-arguably-easier-to-read-on-any-screen-size.&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/node-red-flow-best-practice/#this-now-takes-up-less-space-and-is-arguably-easier-to-read-on-any-screen-size.&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; This now takes up less space and is arguably easier to read on any screen size.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/images/compact-good.png&quot; alt=&quot;This now takes up less space and is arguably easier to read on any screen size.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;don%E2%80%99t-cross-beams-wires&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/node-red-flow-best-practice/#don%E2%80%99t-cross-beams-wires&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Don’t cross &lt;s&gt;beams&lt;/s&gt; wires&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crossed wires are not only hard to read, they can lead to misinterpretation of what a flow actually does. Where possible don’t cross your wires, where you can’t avoid it try to make sure it’s easy for the reader to understand where wires cross as rather than join.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;this-is-confusing%2C-which-change-node-does-the-top-switch-output-link-to%3F&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/node-red-flow-best-practice/#this-is-confusing%2C-which-change-node-does-the-top-switch-output-link-to%3F&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; This is confusing, which change node does the top switch output link to?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/images/wires-bad.png&quot; alt=&quot;This is confusing, which change node does the top switch output link to?&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;this-is-better%2C-much-less-chance-of-confusing-the-change-nodes.&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/node-red-flow-best-practice/#this-is-better%2C-much-less-chance-of-confusing-the-change-nodes.&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; This is better, much less chance of confusing the change nodes.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/images/wires-good.png&quot; alt=&quot;This is better, much less chance of confusing the change nodes.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;don%E2%80%99t-use-link-nodes-in-groups-where-avoidable&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/node-red-flow-best-practice/#don%E2%80%99t-use-link-nodes-in-groups-where-avoidable&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Don’t use link nodes in groups where avoidable&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excessive link nodes within groups can make a flow much harder to understand, where possible use wires to join nodes within a group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;this-is-hard-to-read-and-you-will-end-up-checking-the-link-nodes-again-and-again.&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/node-red-flow-best-practice/#this-is-hard-to-read-and-you-will-end-up-checking-the-link-nodes-again-and-again.&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; This is hard to read and you will end up checking the link nodes again and again.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/images/groupwires-bad.png&quot; alt=&quot;This is hard to read and you will end up checking the link nodes again and again.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;functionally-identical-to-the-example-above%2C-it-should-only-take-a-few-seconds-to-understand-this-flow-now.&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/node-red-flow-best-practice/#functionally-identical-to-the-example-above%2C-it-should-only-take-a-few-seconds-to-understand-this-flow-now.&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Functionally identical to the example above, it should only take a few seconds to understand this flow now.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/images/groupwires-good.png&quot; alt=&quot;Functionally identical to the example above, it should only take a few seconds to understand this flow now.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/12/node-red-flow-best-practice/#conclusion&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working on Node-RED flows as part of a team doesn&#39;t have to be a headache. By following some simple best practices you can make collaboration smooth sailing for everyone involved. So next time you&#39;re starting work on a new Node-RED flow, remember these tips and make life easier for yourself and your teammates.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/11/scaling-node-red-with-diy-tooling/</id>
        <title>Challenges scaling Node-RED with DIY tooling</title>
        <summary>Node-RED is very easy to get up and running for your first instance but what about your 100th?</summary>
        <updated>2022-11-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/11/scaling-node-red-with-diy-tooling/"/>
        <author><name>ZJ van de Weg</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this post, I&#39;m going to share some of the challenges customers face when
scaling Node-RED with Do-It-Yourself tooling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, we&#39;ll talk about
common threads in their journey building their own tooling around Node-RED, its
flows, and deploying them. Node-RED is a visual programming environment for
wiring together hardware devices, APIs and online services in a single
application. It&#39;s great because it&#39;s flexible enough to be used by both
beginners and experts alike; however, going from one instance of Node-RED to 100
isn&#39;t for the faint-hearted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;zero-to-hero-in-a-few-days&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/11/scaling-node-red-with-diy-tooling/#zero-to-hero-in-a-few-days&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Zero to hero in a few days&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re new to Node-RED and are just getting started, the first step is simple:
go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodered.org/&quot;&gt;nodered.org&lt;/a&gt;, download, install and run. There’s no
need to configure anything or set up credentials or security or alerts. You can
get started with Node-RED straight away by simply running it on your machine.
The guides and scripts provided on Node-RED or are more than enough to get
started. You&#39;ll dive right in and start developing your flows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;onto-the-second-instance&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/11/scaling-node-red-with-diy-tooling/#onto-the-second-instance&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Onto the second instance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next instance is a simple copy of the first. You&#39;ll need to make sure that
you are installing the same version on both instances, and that any
configuration files (such as the &lt;code&gt;settings.js&lt;/code&gt;) are also in sync.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second instance improves the first equally. Docs are read again,
improvements are made, and copied over. Life&#39;s good! Although there&#39;s a slight
itch to start automating the setup, it&#39;s ignored. Just too many open questions
on how to achieve it: write scripts in bash? Or can we use Node-RED to manage
Node-RED? Automation can wait, there&#39;s new flows to implement!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;wake-up-call%3B-how-many-of-them-do-we-have%3F&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/11/scaling-node-red-with-diy-tooling/#wake-up-call%3B-how-many-of-them-do-we-have%3F&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Wake-up call; how many of them do we have?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s nothing like a good ol&#39; wake-up call to get you back on track. One of
our team members asked a questions about a buggy flow you&#39;ve got no recollection
of. During the investigation there&#39;s issues left and right; it&#39;s running a much
older version, missing standard packages, the settings are out of date, and the
timezone not set to UTC? Adoption of Node-RED is going quite well, it&#39;s useful
and effective. Gets the job done without fuss. But now there&#39;s toil in
maintaining them; ensure the right tooling is build, properly documented, it
needs dashboards and overviews, lots of work to be done. Not quite business
related, but Node-RED is important for the company, the bosses sure would
approve spending 2 months building these tools!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then something happened—there was a higher priority project to be picked up.
Some tooling could be written for a couple of hours a month, but not two
dedicated months to get it in tip top shape. Better than nothing! Built a
dashboard in Node-RED to keep track of all devices, there&#39;s some scripts and a
few flows that aid in monitoring and maintenance. Scaling further is possible,
but confidence in the tooling isn&#39;t sky high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;data-extraction-at-scale%3B-now-there&#39;s-over-100&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/11/scaling-node-red-with-diy-tooling/#data-extraction-at-scale%3B-now-there&#39;s-over-100&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Data extraction at scale; now there&#39;s over 100&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At FlowForge we&#39;ve got regular conversations with customers managing 100s of
devices. Scaling to that many devices and runtimes requires hours of development
each week alongside monitoring, maintenance, and auditing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a side effect of investing more time into Node-RED and its ecosystem the
organisation has developed a few standards. Standard custom nodes that are
pre-installed (👋 &lt;code&gt;moment.js&lt;/code&gt;), a style guide published for developing flows,
maybe even flow linting: https://github.com/node-red/nrlint&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The security model is fairly decent. One just hopes the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://nl.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chief_Information_Security_Officer&quot;&gt;CISO&lt;/a&gt; doesn&#39;t
inspects them, but it&#39;s a fair bet they won&#39;t; we&#39;re far away from the
headquarters, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many other edge cases itch in the back of our heads, but we can&#39;t focus on those right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/11/scaling-node-red-with-diy-tooling/#conclusion&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Node-RED is a great tool, it&#39;s got many built-in features that make it easy to
get started with no coding experience necessary. Running it at scale, in a
production environment can require a lot of sys-ops and dev-ops time and we
think FlowForge is a great solution to keep that admin and tech debt in check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;re running into these challenges we believe we can help, you can adopt
our &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/install/&quot;&gt;free and open source edition&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/11/respin-docker-compose-01/</id>
        <title>Re-spin of Docker-Compose install package</title>
        <summary>Adding ability to locally build file-server container</summary>
        <updated>2022-11-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/11/respin-docker-compose-01/"/>
        <author><name>Ben Hardill</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/11/flowforge-1-1-released/&quot;&gt;yesterdays 1.1.0 FlowForge release&lt;/a&gt; we noticed a few minor issues with the docker-compose install instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had relied on the fact we are now publishing container images to Docker Hub to install the new &lt;code&gt;flowforge/file-server&lt;/code&gt; container. At this time we are only building images for amd64 and arm64. Further, it was only tagged them with the current release number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To remedy this we tagged v1.1.1 of the docker-compose project in which we have included the required &lt;code&gt;Dockerfile&lt;/code&gt; and resources to build the &lt;code&gt;flowforge/file-server&lt;/code&gt; locally, updated the &lt;code&gt;build-containers.sh&lt;/code&gt; script to build this container. We will also build the published containers for armv7 and include a latest tag going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/11/flowforge-1-1-released/</id>
        <title>FlowForge 1.1 released with persistent file storage</title>
        <summary>A new set of features to improve FlowForge as the best solution for running Node-RED in production in a secure, scalable, and team-based environment.</summary>
        <updated>2022-11-24T18:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/11/flowforge-1-1-released/"/>
        <author><name>Rob Marcer</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Persist files on your FlowForge Projects, publish locally developed flows to dozens of Devices in a few clicks, and use our new interface for managing Project Deployments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re pleased to announce version 1.1 is now available! The latest release of the FlowForge application contains new features, many improvements, and bug fixes. Keep reading for the details of what&#39;s in this release or you can watch our 1 minute roundup video of the new release above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;features&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/11/flowforge-1-1-released/#features&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/998&quot;&gt;Persistent File Storage&lt;/a&gt; We&#39;ve had a great deal of feedback
from our customers that being able to persist files in a project is a vital feature
in Node-RED. In FlowForge 1.1 flows can now create and persist files within
your Projects. We know those files are used in many creative ways and we&#39;re looking
forward to seeing how users improve their Projects using this new feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/user/node-red-tools/&quot;&gt;Import Snapshots from Outside FlowForge&lt;/a&gt; Developers may wish to
work on Node-RED in a local environment but want an easy path to share that with their team. You can now link your Node-RED instances running outside of FlowForge and push Snapshots directly into your FlowForge Projects to leverage FlowForge fully.  With this new feature we&#39;ve made it effortless to push a local build of a project to FlowForge for deployment to your staging and production FlowForge instances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;improvements&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/11/flowforge-1-1-released/#improvements&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/1046&quot;&gt;Project Deployments UX&lt;/a&gt;
We&#39;ve reworked the interface for managing your FlowForge Deployments of Node-RED.
We are seeing FlowForge users deploying their Projects to edge devices at scale.
This is another step towards making it easier for users to manage a large quantity
of devices in their Projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When users change their username, email address, or password they&#39;ll now be
notified through email of changes to ensure they were made by the
user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this release a lot of effort went into the install process, specifically the
local install method. First and foremost; a default Stack and Template will be
installed automatically. That will ensure users get up and running with
Node-RED more quickly. Administrators of each platform can still change Stacks
and Templates when needed. Secondly, the installer now auto generates the
configuration file for Mosquitto, the MQTT broker FlowForge uses. This again should save
administrators time when installing FlowForge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;bug-fixes&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/11/flowforge-1-1-released/#bug-fixes&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Bug Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The v1.0.1 release included a bug fix where &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/1186&quot;&gt;snapshot rollbacks&lt;/a&gt;
didn&#39;t work, which has also been included in v1.1 onwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve fixed the following bugs in this release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When installing the stack during a FlowForge installation the process would quit on Windows &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/installer/issues/62&quot;&gt;#62&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After accepting an invite to join a team, users are no longer seeing a blank page &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/1208&quot;&gt;#1208&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pagination on device deployments wasn&#39;t showing all devices &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/1207&quot;&gt;#1207&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown rendering when selecting the project type wasn&#39;t quite working, fixed now! &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/1171&quot;&gt;#1171&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuous spinner in UI body when entering a new (short) password &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/1280&quot;&gt;#1280&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friendly stack name not shown in the Change Project Stack option list &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/1169&quot;&gt;#1169&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stacks view in the admin area didn&#39;t render properly &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/1260&quot;&gt;#1260&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like the deployments page, pagination for stacks was broken. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/1164&quot;&gt;#1164&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several UX and UI bugs got polished away!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;contributors&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/11/flowforge-1-1-released/#contributors&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Contributors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;d like the thank the following for their contributions to this release:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mikermcneil&quot;&gt;mikermcneil&lt;/a&gt; for their work on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/pull/1301&quot;&gt;#1301&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an open-source project, we welcome community involvement in what we&#39;re building.
If you&#39;re interested in contributing, checkout our &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/contribute/&quot;&gt;guide in the docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;try-it-out&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/11/flowforge-1-1-released/#try-it-out&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Try it out&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As said before, a lot of effort went into the local installer. We&#39;re confident
you can have your own FlowForge running locally in about 30 minutes.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/install/local/&quot;&gt;Get started right away!&lt;/a&gt;
(&lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/install/docker/&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/install/kubernetes/&quot;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt;
are available too!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;d rather use our hosted offering: &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.flowforge.com/account/create?code=RELEASE11&quot;&gt;Sign up for FlowForge Cloud&lt;/a&gt;
with the coupon &lt;strong&gt;RELEASE11&lt;/strong&gt; to get your first project free for a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;upgrading-flowforge&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/11/flowforge-1-1-released/#upgrading-flowforge&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Upgrading FlowForge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://app.flowforge.com/&quot;&gt;FlowForge Cloud&lt;/a&gt; is already running 1.1. To use
persisted files you&#39;ll need to upgrade your projects stack. You&#39;ll be prompted
to do so on the project page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you installed a previous version of FlowForge and want to upgrade, our documentation provides a
guide for &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/install/upgrading/&quot;&gt;upgrading your FlowForge instance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-help&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/11/flowforge-1-1-released/#getting-help&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Getting help&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please check FlowForge&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt; as the answers to many questions are covered there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you hit any problems with the platform please raise an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues&quot;&gt;issue on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.
That also includes if you have any feedback or feature requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chat with us on the &lt;code&gt;#flowforge&lt;/code&gt; channel on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodered.org/slack&quot;&gt;Node-RED Slack workspace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also raise a support ticket by emailing &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:support@flowforge.com&quot;&gt;support@flowforge.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/seed-round-bring-node-red-to-enterprise/</id>
        <title>FlowForge raises $7.25M Seed Round to bring Node-RED to the Enterprise</title>
        <summary>Allowing all developers to integrate IT and OT through low-code</summary>
        <updated>2022-11-03T17:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/seed-round-bring-node-red-to-enterprise/"/>
        <author><name>ZJ van de Weg</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since the &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2021/04/first-deploy/&quot;&gt;launch of FlowForge&lt;/a&gt; in April 2021 our goal has been to
build a low-code, enterprise-ready development platform based on Node-RED. We
wanted to make it easier for enterprises to adopt, integrate, and scale Node-RED
into their existing environments. We published our &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/01/flowforge-01-released/&quot;&gt;first version&lt;/a&gt;
at the start of this year and have continued the journey to the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/flowforge-1-released/&quot;&gt;launch of FlowForge v1.0&lt;/a&gt; just last week. Each of these releases
has moved us towards our goal of creating a platform for integrating the
IT and OT for all organizations, built around an open core.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;flowforge-is-node-red-for-the-enterprise&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/seed-round-bring-node-red-to-enterprise/#flowforge-is-node-red-for-the-enterprise&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; FlowForge is Node-RED for the enterprise&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Node-RED is an incredible tool that has allowed many organizations to quickly
and easily integrate both their IT and OT. The sheer range and variety of
solutions created with Node-RED today go far beyond what we imagined. But we’ve
also seen the challenges faced by companies wanting to take their Node-RED
solutions into production and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where FlowForge comes in. It addresses those challenges by adding
security, collaboration and deployment capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;our-%247.25m-seed-round&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/seed-round-bring-node-red-to-enterprise/#our-%247.25m-seed-round&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Our $7.25M Seed Round&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we’re super excited to announce a $7.25M seed round led by Cota Capital,
joined by Westwave Capital, Uncorrelated Ventures, and Open Core Ventures. This
brings a huge amount of extensive knowledge and experience in IoT, open source,
enterprise-ready software solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This investment will enable us to continue growing the team and platform to
realize our vision of FlowForge being the best way to achieve enterprise-ready
Node-RED. It will enable us to invest back into the core Node-RED project to
further its development. One of our core company principles is around Open
Source Stewardship - the success of FlowForge relies on a strong and successful
Node-RED community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll be bringing more collaboration features to the FlowForge platform to
enable true collaborative, team-based working. We’ll expand our
&lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/user/concepts/#device&quot;&gt;Devices offering&lt;/a&gt; to make it
far easier to run Node-RED wherever it suits your use-case, from data center to
remote edge locations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above all, we’ll be building a company that is open, sustainable, and fun to
work at. We already have some job openings available - check out our
&lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/careers&quot;&gt;jobs board&lt;/a&gt; if you’re interested in joining our
team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in learning more about what we’re doing, or have any
questions, please do &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/contact-us/&quot;&gt;get in touch&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/flowforge-1-released/</id>
        <title>FlowForge 1.0 released</title>
        <summary>FlowForge at 1.0, a huge milestone for us.</summary>
        <updated>2022-10-27T18:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/flowforge-1-released/"/>
        <author><name>Rob Marcer</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Predefined environment variables for your Projects and Devices, manage your Project&#39;s modules and import your existing flows (and credentials) into your FlowForge &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/user/concepts/#project&quot;&gt;Projects&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;!-- Keep reading for the details of what&#39;s in this release or you can watch our 1 minute roundup video of the new release above.  --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re pleased to announce version 1.0 FlowForge is now available. Keep reading for a promotion code to get your first month free on FlowForge. Version 1.0 represents our vision of the base set of features needed for you to get great value from using FlowForge in a production environment. That&#39;s not to say we are done, we will continue to add features, improve our interfaces and fix bugs with the same enthusiasm as we&#39;ve worked towards 1.0. We&#39;d like to hear your feedback on what we will be including in &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/orgs/flowforge/projects/5&quot;&gt;1.1 and beyond&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;features&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/flowforge-1-released/#features&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/841&quot;&gt;Standard Environment Variables set for both Projects and Devices&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Projects now get a set of predefined environment variables that can be used by their flows. These give your flows access to the projects unique id and name. When the flows are deployed to &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/user/concepts/#device&quot;&gt;devices&lt;/a&gt;, they also get the device&#39;s id and name. That makes is easier to deploy flows across multiple devices and have each able to identify itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/405&quot;&gt;Add additional node modules to your projects&lt;/a&gt;
This feature allows you to pre-define additional Node-RED nodes and node modules you may want to be installed in your FlowForge project, making it easier to manage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/835&quot;&gt;Import existing projects into FlowForge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now import your existing flow and credentials files straight into your FlowForge project - making it really easy to move your existing projects into the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;improvements&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/flowforge-1-released/#improvements&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve made a number of improvements to the overall experience of running FlowForge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Editable Stack labels &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/915&quot;&gt;#915&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check for suitable version of Node on Devices &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge-device-agent/issues/37&quot;&gt;#37&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Realtime Project status details in Project overview  &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/990&quot;&gt;#990&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve Template creation &amp;amp; Edit Project Settings UX &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/1041&quot;&gt;#1041&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;bug-fixes&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/flowforge-1-released/#bug-fixes&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Bug Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve fixed the following bugs in this release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/1143&quot;&gt;Pressing return in search box reloads page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/1126&quot;&gt;Vue Router Warn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/forge-ui-components/issues/58&quot;&gt;Kebab menu in Settings breaks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/1096&quot;&gt;flowforge-nr-launcher missing try/catch on http request&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/1145&quot;&gt;Invite with + in email address is incorrectly sanitised&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/forge-ui-components/issues/59&quot;&gt;Table does not sort correctly when empty fields are present&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/929&quot;&gt;4xx Errors not shown in App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/1076&quot;&gt;Inconsistent errors returned from the API&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge-nr-launcher/issues/77&quot;&gt;Module install not working on windows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/1038&quot;&gt;Avatar lettering is mis-allinged when only rendering 1 character&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/968&quot;&gt;it.only is not prohibited&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/966&quot;&gt;No feedback when an API error occurs editing user&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/1040&quot;&gt;Start action is available on a running project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;contributors&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/flowforge-1-released/#contributors&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Contributors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;d like the thank the following for their contributions to this release:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Jozefik&quot;&gt;Jozefik&lt;/a&gt; for their work on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/pull/1082&quot;&gt;Adding limits to admin panel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an open-source project, we welcome community involvement in what we&#39;re building. If you&#39;re interested in contributing, checkout our &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/contribute/&quot;&gt;guide in the docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;try-it-out&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/flowforge-1-released/#try-it-out&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Try it out&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://app.flowforge.com/account/create?code=RELEASE1&quot;&gt;Sign up for FlowForge-Managed Premium&lt;/a&gt; with this link or at the checkout enter the code &lt;strong&gt;RELEASE1&lt;/strong&gt; to get your first project free for a month. As an open source project you can also use &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/install/&quot;&gt;FlowForge-Community&lt;/a&gt; for free, forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;upgrading-flowforge&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/flowforge-1-released/#upgrading-flowforge&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Upgrading FlowForge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our managed &lt;a href=&quot;https://app.flowforge.com/&quot;&gt;FlowForge&lt;/a&gt; is already running 1.0. Upgrade your project Stacks to the latest version to make sure you get all the latest changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you installed a previous version of FlowForge and want to upgrade, our documentation provides a
guide for &lt;a href=&quot;http://flowforge.com/docs/install#upgrade&quot;&gt;upgrading FlowForge on a local server&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-help&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/flowforge-1-released/#getting-help&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Getting help&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you hit any problems with the platform, or have questions to ask, please raise an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues&quot;&gt;issue on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.
That also includes if you have any feedback or feature requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customers of FlowForge Cloud can raise a ticket by emailing support@flowforge.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also have a &lt;code&gt;#flowforge&lt;/code&gt; channel on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodered.org/slack&quot;&gt;Node-RED Slack workspace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/db-migraton-01/</id>
        <title>Scheduled maintenance: Database encryption October 2022</title>
        <summary>Moving to encrypted PostgreSQL storage</summary>
        <updated>2022-10-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/db-migraton-01/"/>
        <author><name>Ben Hardill</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As part of an on-going security &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/product/security/#data-at-rest&quot;&gt;review&lt;/a&gt; of the FlowForge Cloud offering we discovered that the backend database was not using encrypted storage. In keeping with industry best practices we plan to migrate the database to a new instance using encrypted at rest storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;impact&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/db-migraton-01/#impact&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Impact&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customers&#39; Node-RED instances will remain running, though any features that depend on FlowForge will not operate as expected during the migration. This includes user sessions, project and team management, as well as the project nodes for inter-project communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Self-hosted installations are unaffected by this change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;when&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/db-migraton-01/#when&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; When&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The migration will be on 26 October 2022 at 22:00 UTC and is expected to take under 2 hours. The platform will be available as soon as the migration is complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will post updates during the migration period to our Twitter account &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/db-migraton-01/@FlowForgeInc&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/flowforgeinc&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/ff-docker-gcp/</id>
        <title>Install FlowForge Docker on Google Cloud</title>
        <summary>Step by step instructions to get FlowForge Docker running on Google Cloud</summary>
        <updated>2022-10-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/ff-docker-gcp/"/>
        <author><name>Rob Marcer</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As part of our preparations for FlowForge 1.0 we have been testing various real world scenarios to see where we can add to our documentation and where we might be able to improve our releases to make the install process easier for users. As a benefit of that testing we have been able to hone these installation processes and we wanted to share one of those with you today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this first of three articles, we are going to run through the process for installing FlowForge on Google Cloud Platform (GCP) within a virtual machine (VM) using Docker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have set ourselves the goal of delivering a production environment. We want this installation benefit from:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email alerts (emails to users when they are added to teams etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HTTPS access to the install&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FlowForge &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/user/concepts/#device&quot;&gt;Device&lt;/a&gt; deployment via the included MQTT server that comes in our Docker build&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will follow up with a second article covering the process of getting HTTPS running then we will close out the series by covering how to use key features of FlowForge including &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/user/concepts/#device&quot;&gt;Devices&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;prerequisites&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/ff-docker-gcp/#prerequisites&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Prerequisites&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A domain name - We&#39;ve registered flowforge-demo.com to demonstrate these steps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A DNS provider - Our Domain registrar provides a basic DNS service for free&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A GCP account - Google will often give you free service credits on sign up so setting up FlowForge on GCP should not cost you anything for at least a few weeks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An email provider which will allow SMTP connections to send email - To manage users on your FlowForge platform you will need to be able to send emails to them. We have used a Google Workspace account for this purpose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;gcp-vm-creation&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/ff-docker-gcp/#gcp-vm-creation&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; GCP VM Creation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a GCP account, once logged in navigate to Compute Engine then VM Instances. Select Create Instance you should now be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://console.cloud.google.com/compute/instancesAdd?project&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give your instance a name, select a Region and Zone. I have found that the default machine configuration works fine but depending on your project you may wish to change the resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/images/1.png&quot; alt=&quot;GCP Create VM interface&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You now need to allow access to your FlowForge installation from the internet. In the Firewall section tick Allow HTTP traffic and Allow HTTPS traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/images/2.png&quot; alt=&quot;GCP Create VM interface&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up, assigna static IP address to the VM. Click Advanced options, then Networking. Now scroll down until you see Network interfaces and click on default to expand that section. In External IPv4 address select Create IP Address, give it a name than press Reserve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/images/3.png&quot; alt=&quot;GCP Create VM interface&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have reserved your IP it will be shown in the External IPv4 address field, write it down as we will need it later to create the DNS records. Our IP address was 34.125.156.130.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/images/4.png&quot; alt=&quot;GCP Create VM interface&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are now ready to create and boot your VM, scroll to the bottom of the page and press Create. It can take a minute or two for the VM to be ready to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;dns-set-up&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/ff-docker-gcp/#dns-set-up&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; DNS Set Up&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that you can run FlowForge on your newly created GCP VM you will need to set up 2 DNS records. These records are slightly different to what is suggested in the FlowForge install docs. We were keen to be able to run other services on this domain so we set up the following records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/images/5.png&quot; alt=&quot;DNS interface&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DNS changes need to propagate, and depending on your DNS provider, ISP, and other factors, this can take anywhere between a few seconds to 4 hours. Our’s were in place very quickly. To validate the DNS records you can use &lt;code&gt;dig&lt;/code&gt; on either a Mac or Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/images/6.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dig command&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DNS records are set to the IP record we noted down earlier, so we&#39;re good to continue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;flowforge-docker-installation&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/ff-docker-gcp/#flowforge-docker-installation&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; FlowForge Docker Installation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step is to install Docker on our GCP VM. If you return to GCP you should see that your VM is now up and running, you can now click on SSH to connect to your VM. This will open up a browser based SSH session to your VM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/images/7.png&quot; alt=&quot;Access SSH in GCP&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have a Secure Shell (SSH) session open, the first step is to install Docker using the following commands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get update&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install \
   ca-certificates \
   curl \
   gnupg \
   lsb-release
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo mkdir -p /etc/apt/keyrings&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;curl -fsSL https://download.docker.com/linux/debian/gpg | sudo gpg --dearmor -o /etc/apt/keyrings/docker.gpg&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;echo \
  &amp;quot;deb [arch=$(dpkg --print-architecture) signed-by=/etc/apt/keyrings/docker.gpg] https://download.docker.com/linux/debian \
  $(lsb_release -cs) stable&amp;quot; | sudo tee /etc/apt/sources.list.d/docker.list &amp;gt; /dev/null
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get update&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install docker-ce docker-ce-cli containerd.io docker-compose-plugin&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read a lot more detail about what each these commands actually do &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.docker.com/engine/install/debian/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;download-flowforge%E2%80%99s-latest-docker-build&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/ff-docker-gcp/#download-flowforge%E2%80%99s-latest-docker-build&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Download FlowForge’s latest Docker build&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step is to get the codebase for FlowForge onto your VM, to do so you will need to run the following commands. Please note that we are working with our 0.10.0 build, you will need to update the version number in the commands below if you are working with a newer build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use curl to download the files we need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo curl -L https://github.com/flowforge/docker-compose/archive/refs/tags/v0.10.1.tar.gz -o v0.10.1.tar.gz&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make the directory where we will store FlowForge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo mkdir /opt/flowforge&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uncompress FlowForge and save it to the directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo tar zxf v0.10.1.tar.gz --directory /opt/flowforge&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should now have all the code you need for FlowForge in the directory &lt;code&gt;/opt/flowforge/docker-compose-0.10.1&lt;/code&gt;, it should look something like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/images/8.png&quot; alt=&quot;List command output&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;configure-flowforge&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/ff-docker-gcp/#configure-flowforge&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Configure FlowForge&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can now configure FlowForge on your VM. We are going to need to edit two files. Firstly we need to switch into the directory where we just placed FlowForge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd /opt/flowforge/docker-compose-0.10.1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we need to edit the flowforge.yml file, we&#39;re using Nano to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo nano /opt/flowforge/docker-compose-0.10.1/etc/flowforge.yml&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the top of the file you need to update the domain and base_url to match your domain&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/images/9.png&quot; alt=&quot;Domain config&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next we will need to edit the Email Configuration section to match your SMTP provider. Set enabled to true then add in the details provider by your email provider. For example in this case I am using our Google Workspace account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/images/10.png&quot; alt=&quot;Email config&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, you need to update the &lt;code&gt;public_url&lt;/code&gt; for your mqtt broker to match your DNS record.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/images/11.png&quot; alt=&quot;MQTT config&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can now save and close that file, in Nano you can do that by pressing ‘control x’ then ‘y’ then the Return key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we need to edit the &lt;code&gt;docker-compose.yml&lt;/code&gt; file. We will use Nano again to do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo nano /opt/flowforge/docker-compose-0.10.1/docker-compose.yml&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to edit the file to add in to the domain as follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/images/12.png&quot; alt=&quot;Virtual Hosts config&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save and exit from that file, in Nano you can do that by pressing ‘control x’ then ‘y’ then the Return key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;start-flowforge&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/ff-docker-gcp/#start-flowforge&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Start FlowForge&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are now ready to start up FlowForge for the first time, to do so we will use the following command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo docker compose -p flowforge up -d&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The build process will take a few minutes, once it’s completed let’s make sure all the docker containers are running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo docker ps&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/images/13.png&quot; alt=&quot;Docker PS output&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should see 4 running Docker containers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If everything went well you should now be able to access your FlowForge server via the DNS record you created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/10/images/14.png&quot; alt=&quot;FF Login page&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nice, you now have a working instance of FlowForge running on GCP but remember that all traffic is currently running on HTTP so we still have some work to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next article we will cover how to add HTTPS support to this FlowForge installation.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/09/flowforge-010-released/</id>
        <title>FlowForge 0.10 released</title>
        <summary>Secure HTTP end points, Read-only users and Static outbound IPs</summary>
        <updated>2022-09-30T12:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/09/flowforge-010-released/"/>
        <author><name>Rob Marcer</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Secure your HTTP endpoints, create read-only users in your teams and use our static IP address for outbound traffic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep reading for the details of what&#39;s in this release or you can watch our 1 minute roundup video of the new release above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re pleased to announce version 0.10 is now available. The next release of the FlowForge application containing new features, a number of improvements, and bug fixes. Keep reading for a promotion code to get your first month free on FlowForge Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;features&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/09/flowforge-010-released/#features&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/578&quot;&gt;Secure HTTP Endpoints&lt;/a&gt;
We&#39;ve added the ability for you to secure your HTTP endpoints. You can now control who can access Dashboards or API endpoints you create in FlowForge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/657&quot;&gt;Read-only Users&lt;/a&gt;
We&#39;ve added a new user role for Read-only access. This will allow users to login to your FlowForge project and view the Node-RED flows without them being able to edit anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/CloudProject/issues/59&quot;&gt;Static Outbound IP Addresses&lt;/a&gt;
We&#39;ve updated FlowForge Cloud so that all outbound traffic from your projects now comes from a single IP address. When trying to access a remote resource such as a database it is often a requirement for the IP address the traffic comes from to be fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;improvements&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/09/flowforge-010-released/#improvements&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve made a number of improvements to the overall experience of running FlowForge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow both key and component in a ff-data-table column definition &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/forge-ui-components/issues/43&quot;&gt;#43&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Default Stack and Templates &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/989&quot;&gt;#989&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide platform containers and base stack container for administrators &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/917&quot;&gt;#917&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;bug-fixes&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/09/flowforge-010-released/#bug-fixes&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Bug Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve fixed the following bugs in this release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/917&quot;&gt;Provide platform containers and base stack container for administrators&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/983&quot;&gt;User names can be same (but different case)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/463&quot;&gt;User list not refreshing after changing user details&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/986&quot;&gt;Navigating directly to a device page gets the wrong team selected&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/941&quot;&gt;Node-RED Isn&#39;t ready when FlowForge app says it is running following a project restart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/923&quot;&gt;Invitations left for deleted teams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/1024&quot;&gt;Following email verification link twice throws error&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge-device-agent/issues/21&quot;&gt;Agent does not log stderr from the Node-RED process&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/948&quot;&gt;On Kubernetes project names can not start with a number&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/930&quot;&gt;When creating projects stack options do not wrap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/979&quot;&gt;Save button in admin user-edit dialog doesn&#39;t close dialog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/911&quot;&gt;Setting UI doesn&#39;t allow me to update settings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;contributors&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/09/flowforge-010-released/#contributors&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Contributors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;d like the thank the following for their contributions to this release:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Pezmc&quot;&gt;Pezmc&lt;/a&gt; for their work on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/pull/949&quot;&gt;Add device count and project counts by type to admin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ArshErgon&quot;&gt;ArshErgon&lt;/a&gt; for their work on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/pull/977&quot;&gt;Update vue component name for NoVerifiedEmail.vue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an open-source project, we welcome the community involvement in what we&#39;re building. If you&#39;re interested in contributing, checkout our &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/contribute/&quot;&gt;guide in the docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;try-it-out&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/09/flowforge-010-released/#try-it-out&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Try it out&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://app.flowforge.com/account/create?code=RELEASE010&quot;&gt;Sign up for FlowForge Cloud&lt;/a&gt; with this link  or at the checkout enter the code &lt;strong&gt;RELEASE010&lt;/strong&gt; to get your first project free for a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;upgrading-flowforge&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/09/flowforge-010-released/#upgrading-flowforge&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Upgrading FlowForge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://app.flowforge.com/&quot;&gt;FlowForge Cloud&lt;/a&gt; is already running 0.10 and the stacks updated. Upgrade your project stacks to the latest version to make sure you get all the latest changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you installed a previous version of FlowForge and want to upgrade, our documentation provides a
guide for &lt;a href=&quot;http://flowforge.com/docs/install#upgrade&quot;&gt;upgrading FlowForge on a local server&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-help&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/09/flowforge-010-released/#getting-help&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Getting help&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you hit any problems with the platform, or have questions to ask, please do
raise an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues&quot;&gt;issue on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.
That also includes if you have any feedback or feature requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customers of FlowForge Cloud can raise a ticket by emailing support@flowforge.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also have a &lt;code&gt;#flowforge&lt;/code&gt; channel on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodered.org/slack&quot;&gt;Node-RED Slack workspace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/09/static-ips/</id>
        <title>Static Outbound IP Addresses</title>
        <summary>Static IP addresses are here for your FlowForge Cloud projects’ outbound connections</summary>
        <updated>2022-09-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/09/static-ips/"/>
        <author><name>Rob Marcer</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On Friday last week we updated FlowForge Cloud to use a static IP address for outbound traffic. This will allow you to predict which IP address your traffic will come from for example when traversing a firewall or accessing a remote database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will need to manually suspend then start each of your projects (a restart will not move your projects to the fixed IP address). Once that action is completed all outbound connections will come from one of our static IP address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any inbound traffic should still use the hostname assigned to each of your projects, you cannot use our IP address to route http traffic to your projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can view our IP address in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/tree/main/docs/cloud#ip-addresses&quot;&gt;Docs&lt;/a&gt; section of our website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to stay up to date with our latest releases you can do so on &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog&quot;&gt;our blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/09/flowforge-09-released/</id>
        <title>FlowForge 0.9 released</title>
        <summary>Suspended projects, login with email and Team Types</summary>
        <updated>2022-09-01T12:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/09/flowforge-09-released/"/>
        <author><name></name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Suspend your projects when you don&#39;t need them, login with either your username or email, and introducing Team Types&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep reading for the details of what&#39;s in this release our you can watch our 1 minute roundup video of the new release above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re pleased to announce version 0.9 is now available. The next release of the FlowForge application containing new features, a number of improvements, and bug fixes. Keep reading for a promotion code to get your first month free on FlowForge Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;features&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/09/flowforge-09-released/#features&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/893&quot;&gt;Suspend Projects&lt;/a&gt;
Sometimes you want to put a project to one side for a while, maybe your development has stalled or you&#39;re waiting on something external to be ready. Perhaps you don&#39;t need it to be running all the time. With the 0.9 release we&#39;ve added the ability to suspend a project. Once suspended, your flows are safely stored in the platform database, but Node-RED isn&#39;t running and the project doesn&#39;t consume any resources. In FlowForge Cloud we do not charge you for suspended projects - you only pay when the project is running.
Your project will be there ready to start back up when you need it with just one click.
Remember that any context data or anything written to the filesystem will not persist through a restart or a suspend of a project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alongside this change, we&#39;ve removed the option to &#39;stop&#39; a project. That option would only stop Node-RED, but the underlying container would still be running, consuming resources. With Node-RED 3.0 adding the ability to stop the flows, but still be able to edit them, that provides a much better user experience.
You can still restart the Node-RED process from the Forge app as before for example when you have updated a package in your flows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/733&quot;&gt;Team Types&lt;/a&gt;
We&#39;ve introduced another concept into the platform with this release. Team Types will allow us to offer more advanced features to teams on FlowForge Cloud. You won&#39;t see much difference in this release but it allows us to build on in future releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/695&quot;&gt;PostHog Analytics&lt;/a&gt;
We&#39;ve changed the analytics tooling integrated into the platform. With this release, we&#39;ve deprecated the use of Plausible Analytics as it didn&#39;t quite provide the sort of insight we wanted. We now integrate with &lt;a href=&quot;https://posthog.com/&quot;&gt;PostHog&lt;/a&gt;. They share our ethos and approach to open source and self hosting - something you can take advantage of if you&#39;re running your own FlowForge platform.
For FlowForge Cloud, the data is sent to our PostHog account so we can better understand how the platform is being used. If you&#39;re running your own instance, the information is only captured if you configure it with your own PostHog instance details - it does not send any data back to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/856&quot;&gt;Login with email&lt;/a&gt;
A common problem that we&#39;ve seen from users is trying to login with their email address instead of their username. As of 0.9 you can now enter either at the login screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/774&quot;&gt;Custom Dashboard Path&lt;/a&gt;
If you are using the Node-RED Dashboard set of nodes, you can now change the path where the dashboard will be served from. The default is still &lt;code&gt;/ui&lt;/code&gt; but you can now move that onto &lt;code&gt;/&lt;/code&gt; or anything else. This is helpful when migrating existing projects over to FlowForge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;improvements&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/09/flowforge-09-released/#improvements&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve made a number of improvements to the overall experience of running FlowForge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improvements to the FlowForge Theme &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/pull/883&quot;&gt;#883&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upper-case characters in Project Names &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/546&quot;&gt;#546&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Password reset requests are logged&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/773&quot;&gt;#773&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Admin can manually verify users email &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/692&quot;&gt;#902&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;bug-fixes&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/09/flowforge-09-released/#bug-fixes&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Bug Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve fixed the following bugs in this release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/875&quot;&gt;Cannot edit template settings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge-nr-project-nodes/issues/10&quot;&gt;Project Link Nodes Appear in CE Install&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge-nr-project-nodes/issues/14&quot;&gt;Project Link Nodes MQTT Connection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge-nr-theme/issues/19&quot;&gt;Theme shows white characters on white background&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge-device-agent/issues/27&quot;&gt;Changing Project on device doesn&#39;t remove old modules&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge-device-agent/issues/30&quot;&gt;Device Agent and Node-RED use different time in logs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;contributors&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/09/flowforge-09-released/#contributors&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Contributors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;d like the thank the following for their contributions to this release:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bonanitech&quot;&gt;Bonantech&lt;/a&gt; for his work &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge-nr-theme/commit/30e21a3777dc3438ef206157ee9110728011f59c&quot;&gt;cleaning up the theme CSS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an open-source project, we welcome the community involvement in what we&#39;re building. If you&#39;re interested in contributing, checkout our &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/contribute/&quot;&gt;guide in the docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;try-it-out&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/09/flowforge-09-released/#try-it-out&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Try it out&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://app.flowforge.com/account/create&quot;&gt;Sign up for FlowForge Cloud&lt;/a&gt; and at the checkout enter the code &lt;strong&gt;RELEASE09&lt;/strong&gt; to get your first project free for a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;upgrading-flowforge&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/09/flowforge-09-released/#upgrading-flowforge&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Upgrading FlowForge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://app.flowforge.com/&quot;&gt;FlowForge Cloud&lt;/a&gt; is already running 0.9 and the stacks updated. Upgrade your project stacks to the latest version and start using the Project Link nodes now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you installed a previous version of FlowForge and want to upgrade, our documentation provides a
guide for &lt;a href=&quot;http://flowforge.com/docs/install#upgrade&quot;&gt;upgrading FlowForge on a local server&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-help&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/09/flowforge-09-released/#getting-help&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Getting help&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you hit any problems with the platform, or have questions to ask, please do
raise an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues&quot;&gt;issue on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.
That also includes if you have any feedback or feature requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customers of FlowForge Cloud can raise a ticket by emailing support@flowforge.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also have a &lt;code&gt;#flowforge&lt;/code&gt; channel on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodered.org/slack&quot;&gt;Node-RED Slack workspace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/08/community-news-06/</id>
        <title>Community News</title>
        <summary>News from the FlowForge and Node-RED communities</summary>
        <updated>2022-08-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/08/community-news-06/"/>
        <author><name></name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the FlowForge newsletter, a regular roundup of what`s happening with both FlowForge and the wider Node-RED community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#39;ve got something that you&#39;d like us to share please email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:contact@flowforge.com&quot;&gt;contact@flowforge.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/08/flowforge-08-released/&quot;&gt;FlowForge 0.8 &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Version 0.8 was released, notable features include the new Project Link nodes for sharing data between projects, and the ability to stop and start flows within Node-RED.
We&#39;ve updated the format of our release posts as well to detail all the user facing changes, from new Features through to small improvements and bugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tomshardware.com/how-to/raspberry-pi-pico-w-node-red&quot;&gt;Raspberry Pi Pico with Node-RED&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/biglesp&quot;&gt;Les Pounder&lt;/a&gt; Has published a great tutorial on communicating with the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.raspberrypi.com/products/raspberry-pi-pico/&quot;&gt;Raspberry Pi Pico W&lt;/a&gt; and Node-RED. He shows you how to capture data from an environmental sensor then display this on a dashboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/07/new-projecttype/&quot;&gt;Medium Projects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We&#39;ve added a second size of project to FlowForge Cloud. A bigger project type with more resources available to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.golioth.io/how-to-use-node-red-to-control-iot-devices-on-golioth/&quot;&gt;Using Node-RED to control IoT Devices on Golioth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Our friends at &lt;a href=&quot;https://golioth.io/&quot;&gt;Golioth&lt;/a&gt; have published an article on how to use Node-RED to control and process data from IoT Devices connected to their platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://discourse.nodered.org/t/node-red-2-2-3-and-3-0-2-released/66018&quot;&gt;Node-RED 3.0.2 and 2.2.3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Node-RED 3.0.2 has been released fixing some bugs in the 3.0.0 release, The Node-RED 2.x stream has also had a maintenance release with many of the fixes in 3.0 back-ported. As usual these are already available as stacks on FlowForge Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/08/flowforge-08-released/</id>
        <title>FlowForge 0.8 released</title>
        <summary>Inter-Project Communication, Default Teams, and realtime device management.</summary>
        <updated>2022-08-04T12:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/08/flowforge-08-released/"/>
        <author><name></name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Easily pass messages between your projects on the cloud or devices, UX improvements, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep reading for  the details of whats in this release our you can watch our 1 minute roundup video of the new release above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re pleased to announce version 0.8 is now available. The next release of the FlowForge application containing new features, a number of improvements, and bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;features&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/08/flowforge-08-released/#features&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/662&quot;&gt;Project Link Nodes&lt;/a&gt;
We&#39;ve introduced our first custom FlowForge nodes to the palette of new projects. The Project Link nodes allow you to easily pass data between different projects within the same team.
These projects can be running in the cloud or on devices, with the communication powered by our own internal MQTT broker.
Try these out today on FlowForge Cloud by creating a new project or updating your existing project&#39;s stack. There&#39;s more information in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge-nr-project-nodes/blob/main/README.md&quot;&gt;README&lt;/a&gt; for the nodes.
For local installs of FlowForge, the nodes are only available with an Enterprise Edition license.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/08/images/ProjectLink.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/839&quot;&gt;Start &amp;amp; Stop Flows&lt;/a&gt;
Node-RED 3.0 &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodered.org/blog/2022/07/14/version-3-0-released#editing-stopped-flows&quot;&gt;introduced a new feature&lt;/a&gt; that allows you to stop your flows from processing requests while still being able to work in the editor and deploy changes. We&#39;ve now enabled this feature within FlowForge for projects running a Node-RED 3.x stack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/298&quot;&gt;Default Team&lt;/a&gt;
If you are a member of multiple teams you can now set your preferred default saving you from having to change teams each time you log in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;improvements&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/08/flowforge-08-released/#improvements&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve made a number of improvements to the overall experience of running FlowForge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Devices now communicate to the Forge application over MQTT instead of polling &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/754&quot;&gt;#754&lt;/a&gt;. You&#39;ll need to update your Device Agent to the latest version to take advantage of this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The table views have had a major overhaul allowing you to sort and search items &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/forge-ui-components/issues/28&quot;&gt;#28&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the application receives an error you now see a notification in the UI. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/771&quot;&gt;#771&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Verification email page has been cleaned up &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/718&quot;&gt;#718&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The initial Thank-you page has been cleaned up &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/648&quot;&gt;#648&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;bug-fixes&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/08/flowforge-08-released/#bug-fixes&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Bug Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve fixed the following bugs in this release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/793&quot;&gt;Logo Distorted in Safari&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/729&quot;&gt;LocalFS Install doesn&#39;t check for Build Tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/pull/842&quot;&gt;Users with Expired passwords can create teams&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/pull/790&quot;&gt;Click-jacking Vulnerability&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/pull/824&quot;&gt;Users with can create teams without verifying email&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge-nr-storage/issues/17&quot;&gt;Occasional Timeout when deploying flows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/833&quot;&gt;Notification of member deletion contains internal ID&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/334&quot;&gt;Pressing Enter in the Team Delete modal triggers cancel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/751&quot;&gt;Node-Red Isn&#39;t ready when Forge app says it is running (Docker)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;contributors&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/08/flowforge-08-released/#contributors&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Contributors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;d like the thank the following for their contributions to this release:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/HaroldPetersInskipp&quot;&gt;HaroldPetersInskipp&lt;/a&gt; helped &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/pull/812&quot;&gt;updating our documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Steveorevo&quot;&gt;Steveorevo&lt;/a&gt; also &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/pull/818&quot;&gt;updated our documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an open-source project, we welcome the community involvement in what we&#39;re building. If you&#39;re interested in contributing, checkout our &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/contribute/&quot;&gt;guide in the docs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;upgrading-flowforge&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/08/flowforge-08-released/#upgrading-flowforge&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Upgrading FlowForge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://app.flowforge.com/&quot;&gt;FlowForge Cloud&lt;/a&gt; is already running 0.8 and the stacks updated. Upgrade your project stacks to the latest version and start using the Project Link nodes now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you installed a previous version of FlowForge and want to upgrade, our documentation provides a
guide for &lt;a href=&quot;http://flowforge.com/docs/install#upgrade&quot;&gt;upgrading FlowForge on a local server&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-help&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/08/flowforge-08-released/#getting-help&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Getting help&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you hit any problems with the platform, or have questions to ask, please do
raise an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues&quot;&gt;issue on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.
That also includes if you have any feedback or feature requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customers of FlowForge Cloud can raise a ticket by emailing support@flowforge.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also have a &lt;code&gt;#flowforge&lt;/code&gt; channel on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodered.org/slack&quot;&gt;Node-RED Slack workspace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/07/new-projecttype/</id>
        <title>Introducing Medium Projects on FlowForge Cloud</title>
        <summary>A bigger project with more resources</summary>
        <updated>2022-07-22T12:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/07/new-projecttype/"/>
        <author><name></name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve added a second size of project to FlowForge Cloud. A bigger project type with more resources available to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/07/flowforge-07-released/&quot;&gt;0.7 release&lt;/a&gt; introduced the concept of Project Types. This allows platforms to provide different sizes of projects, varying the memory/cpu or features available within a given type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we&#39;ve put this feature to work on FlowForge Cloud by introducing the new &lt;strong&gt;Medium Project&lt;/strong&gt; type.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/07/images/project-type.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medium projects have 3 times the resources of the existing Small type, allowing for more complex flows and larger message objects. This will be useful to business users looking to process complex sets of data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Medium project is priced at $50 a month and we&#39;ll be adding new features to this project type in the coming months to further enhance the value of this new tier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don&#39;t currently support directly upgrading a project between types, but that is in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/595&quot;&gt;plan for the future&lt;/a&gt;. In the meantime, you can use the &#39;Export Project&#39; feature on a project&#39;s settings tab to copy it over into a new Medium type project.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/07/flowforge-07-released/</id>
        <title>FlowForge 0.7 released</title>
        <summary>Rollbacks, Device Environment Variables and a FlowForge Theme</summary>
        <updated>2022-07-07T12:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/07/flowforge-07-released/"/>
        <author><name></name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Rollback projects to a previous snapshot, improvements in using Devices, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep reading for  the details of whats in this release our you can watch our 1 min roundup video of the new release above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re pleased to announce version 0.7 is now available. the next release of the FlowForge application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;features&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/07/flowforge-07-released/#features&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/587&quot;&gt;Rollback&lt;/a&gt;
FlowForge is about running Node-RED at any scale, part of that scale is having multiple users collaborate on the same project. When you are collaborating with people it&#39;s important to be able to go back in time to a known working state. As part of that we are introducing rollbacks, this means that you can now take a snapshot of your project at a point in time and then make changes safe in the knowledge that you can rollback to that previous snapshot if you need to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/680&quot;&gt;Device Environment Variables&lt;/a&gt;
In the last release we introduced the concept of devices. We&#39;re already learning from how these are used and one feature we&#39;ve added in 0.7 is Device Environment Variables. You have been able to set Environment Variables at the project level but when deploying a snapshot to multiple devices you may want to override these values for each device, for example to set a site ID. With device specific variable users are enabled to differentiate based on the context in their flows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge-nr-theme/&quot;&gt;FlowForge Theme&lt;/a&gt;
Now that we have a stronger visual identity in the Forge application we have continued that work through to the Node-RED editor. If you create or upgrade a project with a Node-RED 3.0 stack you will see a different theme in the editor. It&#39;s still very much Node-RED but just has some subtle hints to tie it back to the FlowForge application. We will continue to iterate on this to further integrate the experience between FlowForge and Node-RED in both directions.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/07/images/ff-07-theme.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/380&quot;&gt;ProjectTypes&lt;/a&gt;
The introduction of ProjectTypes is a way to group Stacks together that share common characteristics - such as memory/cpu limits, or the availability of particular features. In platforms with billing enabled, such as our own FlowForge Cloud, the ProjectTypes can have different price points set on them. Within FlowForge Cloud, you&#39;ll see we&#39;ve introduced the Small ProjectType - which applies to all existing projects on the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/694&quot;&gt;Stack Versions&lt;/a&gt;
This allows an admin to link different stacks together in their lineage. This allows administrators to nudge users to new Node-RED versions or upgrade pre-installed dependencies when running in a container environment. Any users with projects on an old version will be prompted that there is an update available, making it even easier to stay up to date with Node-RED versions when you build your flows on FlowForge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;improvements&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/07/flowforge-07-released/#improvements&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve made a number of improvements to the overall experience of running FlowForge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Team Switch menu has been moved to a more prominent position in the interface, this also makes it easier to see how to create a new team. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/616&quot;&gt;#616&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notifications have had an overhaul, you will now see waiting invites on all pages. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/515&quot;&gt;#515&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you are running your own copy of FlowForge you can now see the version details in the admin pages &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/655&quot;&gt;#655&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Device polling is no longer an INFO level message  filling the log on your devices &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge-device-agent/issues/10&quot;&gt;#10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;bug-fixes&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/07/flowforge-07-released/#bug-fixes&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Bug Fixes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve fixed the following bugs in this release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge-device-agent/issues/7&quot;&gt;Devices now listen on all Interfaces allowing you to run local http servers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge-device-agent/issues/7&quot;&gt;Solved an issue where a device gets an error  unknown device&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/507&quot;&gt;The Audit Log in the Forge app displays the correct IP when a user logs in to Node-RED&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/507&quot;&gt;Resolved an issue with devices downloading snaphots from legacy stacks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/735&quot;&gt;Fixed an error where objects in the node-red log would hang the log page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/745&quot;&gt;Next Billing Date is now shown correctly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/689&quot;&gt;Fixed a bug where the loading page would flash during polling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;upgrading-flowforge&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/07/flowforge-07-released/#upgrading-flowforge&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Upgrading FlowForge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://app.flowforge.com/&quot;&gt;FlowForge Cloud&lt;/a&gt; is already running 0.7 - ready for
you to try out rollbacks and the new theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you installed a previous version of FlowForge and want to upgrade, our documentation provides a
guide for &lt;a href=&quot;http://flowforge.com/docs/install#upgrade&quot;&gt;upgrading FlowForge on a local server&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-help&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/07/flowforge-07-released/#getting-help&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Getting help&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you hit any problems with the platform, or have questions to ask, please do
raise an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues&quot;&gt;issue on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.
That also includes if you have any feedback or feature requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customers of FlowForge Cloud can raise a ticket by emailing support@flowforge.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also have a &lt;code&gt;#flowforge&lt;/code&gt; channel on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodered.org/slack&quot;&gt;Node-RED Slack workspace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/06/flowforge-06-released/</id>
        <title>FlowForge 0.6 released</title>
        <summary>Adding Devices to the platform</summary>
        <updated>2022-06-19T12:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/06/flowforge-06-released/"/>
        <author><name>Nick O&#39;Leary</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Node-RED is well known for its role in IoT solutions - which often means running
flows on devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was something we always wanted to support in FlowForge and with this release
we&#39;re taking the next steps in that direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;devices&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/06/flowforge-06-released/#devices&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Devices&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release includes the first alpha release of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge-device-agent&quot;&gt;FlowForge Device Agent&lt;/a&gt;. This is a small piece of node.js software that can be
installed on a device, such as a Raspberry Pi. It connects back to the FlowForge
platform to get the Node-RED flows it should be running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This builds on the work we added in 0.5 that lets you register the device,
generate credentials for it and pick which Project in your team it should be assigned
to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It makes it super simple to start developing your flows in FlowForge and push them
out to a group of devices with a couple clicks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s plenty of work still to come on the Devices feature. Under the covers
it uses an HTTP polling approach to check for updates. That was a pragmatic choice
to get something working - but it isn&#39;t our long term strategy. We&#39;ll be working
towards a more IoT-native MQTT/WebSocket appoach in the coming releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/user/devices/&quot;&gt;Devices documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/446&quot;&gt;Epic #446 - Devices&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;snapshots&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/06/flowforge-06-released/#snapshots&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Snapshots&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release adds the ability to create Snapshots of your projects. These are
point-in-time backups of your project&#39;s flows, credentials and settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this release we support &lt;em&gt;creating&lt;/em&gt; snapshots and pushing them to devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don&#39;t have the ability to revert a project back to a previous snapshot, but
that will come soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/user/snapshots/&quot;&gt;Snapshot documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/587&quot;&gt;Story #587 - Snapshot/Rollback&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;other-updates&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/06/flowforge-06-released/#other-updates&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Other updates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond these headline features, there are a number of smaller, but just as useful
items in this release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve continued with the rebranding work started in 0.5 with some more improvements
to the overall UX of the platform. Little touches like placeholder loading graphics
give the UI a more responsive feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you log out of the platform we now also automatically log you out of any
Node-RED editor sessions you have open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;upgrading-flowforge&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/06/flowforge-06-released/#upgrading-flowforge&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Upgrading FlowForge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://app.flowforge.com/&quot;&gt;FlowForge Cloud&lt;/a&gt; is already running 0.6 - ready for
you to start creating snapshots and adding devices right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you installed a previous version of FlowForge and want to upgrade, our documentation provides a
guide for &lt;a href=&quot;http://flowforge.com/docs/install#upgrade&quot;&gt;upgrading FlowForge on a local server&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-help&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/06/flowforge-06-released/#getting-help&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Getting help&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you hit any problems with the platform, or have questions to ask, please do
raise an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues&quot;&gt;issue on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That also includes if you have any feedback or feature requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also have a &lt;code&gt;#flowforge&lt;/code&gt; channel on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodered.org/slack&quot;&gt;Node-RED Slack workspace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/05/sign-up-for-flowforge-cloud/</id>
        <title>FlowForge open for everybody</title>
        <summary>Sign up and start a new Node-RED project within a minute!</summary>
        <updated>2022-05-25T09:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/05/sign-up-for-flowforge-cloud/"/>
        <author><name>ZJ van de Weg</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;FlowForge wants to enable everyone to build workflows in Node-RED. Since announcing
&lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/02/announcing-flowforge-cloud/&quot;&gt;FlowForge Cloud&lt;/a&gt;
two months ago we&#39;ve had a waiting list for users to sign up to. That allowed us
to control the pace we were bringing new users onto the platform, learning what
is needed to scale up our platform and continue to improve our first user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we have removed the waiting list. Anyone can sign up to FlowForge and start a
new Node-RED project in under a minute!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;max-w-md m-auto&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a class=&quot;ff-btn ff-btn--primary&quot; href=&quot;https://app.flowforge.com/account/create&quot;&gt;Sign up&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-we-offer&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/05/sign-up-for-flowforge-cloud/#what-we-offer&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; What we offer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides the sub minute time to start a new Node-RED project, there&#39;s many more
features our offering includes. Two we&#39;d like to highlight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To start our blog highlight reel: Collaboration. FlowForge allows you to work
with a team on your flows. There&#39;s the ability to create multiple users, each
with their own credentials that can alter the flows on Node-RED, and it&#39;s
execution environment like for example the &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/user/envvar/&quot;&gt;environments variables&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/user/changestack&quot;&gt;stacks&lt;/a&gt;. These allow
a user to select the execution environment for their Node-RED project. For example; the
Node-RED version being used. Combined with the ability for one to copy a project
to a new stack, this allows FlowForge users to copy their project to the Node-RED
3.0-beta stack to validate their solutions will continue to work on the new release
without disrupting their main project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;our-roadmap&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/05/sign-up-for-flowforge-cloud/#our-roadmap&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Our roadmap&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently we&#39;re working towards our 0.6 release. The main feature of this release
will be support for Devices. This will allow you to send a snapshot of a project
to a Node-RED instance running outside of the FlowForge platform and update the flows
remotely. Remote devices will run our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge-device-agent&quot;&gt;agent&lt;/a&gt;
to communicate with the FlowForge Cloud project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the first iteration will be considered an Alpha release, by shipping early and often, it lets us get
welcome feedback from our users and the wider community - helping to shape the future direction.
It also allows users to start validating the feature for their own proof of concept projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the next few months we&#39;re continuing to drive development of the platform
across a number of areas - including further improvements to the Device feature.
But also looking at new Enterprise-ready features, such as Single-Sign On integration
and more tools to make collaboration even easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We intend to grow our offering so that FlowForge remains the best way to run
Node-RED.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay informed by registering for our newsletter!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/05/flowforge-05-released/</id>
        <title>FlowForge 0.5 released</title>
        <summary>Bringing a new look to the platform</summary>
        <updated>2022-05-12T12:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/05/flowforge-05-released/"/>
        <author><name>Nick O&#39;Leary</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The cycle continues with our next regularly scheduled release, bringing a fresh
new look to the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since joining the team, Joe has been hard at work bringing a more consistent
design language to what we&#39;re doing. This release brings a lot of his hardwork
to the platform itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s more to be done on the individual pages of the platform, but this
gives us a solid framework to build on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/05/images/ff-05-dashboard.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/430&quot;&gt;Epic #430 - Rebrand Forage App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;copying-projects&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/05/flowforge-05-released/#copying-projects&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Copying Projects&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the usage scenarios we want to support is having an easy way to have separate
test and production environments. The previous release added the ability to configure
environment variables on individual projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release unlocks the next piece of the puzzle - making it easy to copy flows
between projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Project settings page has two new options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy Project lets you create a complete copy of the project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Export to existing project lets you copy over selected aspects of the project
over to another project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both cases, you get to pick what parts of the project should be copied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/268&quot;&gt;Epic #268 - Export Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/271&quot;&gt;Story #271 - Duplicate Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/272&quot;&gt;Story #272 - Export to Existing Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;improve-billing-information&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/05/flowforge-05-released/#improve-billing-information&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Improve Billing Information&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve been getting some great feedback from the users of FlowForge Cloud. One of the
areas we identified as needing some more clarity was around the point users are
asked to setup their billing information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/563&quot;&gt;Story #563 - Improve Information on billing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;edge-devices&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/05/flowforge-05-released/#edge-devices&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Edge Devices&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst we always want to deliver new functionality to end users in each release,
sometimes bits of work don&#39;t fit naturally into a single four week iteration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#39;s the case here with some of the preliminary work we&#39;ve done to introduce
the idea of Edge Devices to the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal here is to provide a way to easily deploy and manage Node-RED projects
on remote devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release introduces a bunch of work to the core app and front-end to begin
introducing the concept of a Device. It includes the basic workflows for registering
a device on the platform and being able to assign it to a team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole feature is hidden behind a feature flag so users on FlowForge Cloud won&#39;t
see any of this quite yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next release will introduce the Edge Agent piece of this - the bit that runs
on devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/446&quot;&gt;Epic #446 - Devices&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;upgrading-flowforge&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/05/flowforge-05-released/#upgrading-flowforge&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Upgrading FlowForge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you installed a previous version of FlowForge  and want to upgrade, our documentation provides a
guide for &lt;a href=&quot;http://flowforge.com/docs/install#upgrade&quot;&gt;upgrading FlowForge on a local server&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-help&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/05/flowforge-05-released/#getting-help&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Getting help&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you hit any problems with the platform, or have questions to ask, please do
raise an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues&quot;&gt;issue on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That also includes if you have any feedback or feature requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also have a &lt;code&gt;#flowforge&lt;/code&gt; channel on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodered.org/slack&quot;&gt;Node-RED Slack workspace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/05/node-red-3-beta-stack/</id>
        <title>Node-RED 3.0 Beta Stack</title>
        <summary>Try out the next major Node-RED release</summary>
        <updated>2022-05-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/05/node-red-3-beta-stack/"/>
        <author><name></name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The first beta of Node-RED 3.0 is here and FlowForge is ready for you to try it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we released &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/04/flowforge-04-released/&quot;&gt;FlowForge 0.4&lt;/a&gt; last month we talked about allowing users to select the stack their project runs on.
Until now we&#39;ve only offered one stack which has been the latest Node-RED release (2.2.2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday the first beta of Node-RED 3.0 was &lt;a href=&quot;https://discourse.nodered.org/t/node-red-3-0-0-beta-1-released/62124&quot;&gt;released&lt;/a&gt;, so as of today we have added a choice of stacks to FlowForge Cloud. You can stick with the &lt;em&gt;Default&lt;/em&gt; and use Node-RED 2.2.2 or if you want to try out the beta you can select &lt;em&gt;Node-RED-3.0.0-beta-1&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/05/images/beta_stack.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Selecting the beta Stack&quot; title=&quot;Selecting the beta Stack&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FlowForge is the best way to run multiple Node-RED instances at different versions. Beta releases are exciting to try out, but you don&#39;t want to risk your production applications with an early upgrade. FlowForge makes it easy to create a new project to try things out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ll continue to update the stack choice with each beta when they are released.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/04/flowforge-04-released/</id>
        <title>FlowForge 0.4 released</title>
        <summary>Getting ready for Node-RED 3.0</summary>
        <updated>2022-04-14T12:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/04/flowforge-04-released/"/>
        <author><name></name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This release of the FlowForge adds a seemingly small, but significant new feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodered.org/about/releases/&quot;&gt;Node-RED 3.0 fast approaching&lt;/a&gt; we&#39;ve been making sure we are ready to support this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;upgrading-node-red&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/04/flowforge-04-released/#upgrading-node-red&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Upgrading Node-RED&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of FlowForge is to be the best way to run Node-RED at any scale, whether that&#39;s many users or many instances. Node-RED is a constantly developing as a platform and therefore part of running Node-RED is also upgrading the version you are running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the 0.4 release today we&#39;ve made that super simple in FlowForge. Last month we introduced the concept of &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/user/concepts/#project-stack&quot;&gt;Project Stacks&lt;/a&gt;. One of the key elements of a Stack was the version of Node-RED in use. Initially this may have seemed fairly basic, when you create a new project you usually want to use the latest version of Node-RED. However what happens when a new version is released and you have an existing project?
Now you can change the stack that a project is running on, which in turn will change the version of Node-RED. This is a simple process from the project settings, it only requires a short period of downtime while the project restarts on the new stack, typically around 10-15 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our driver to get this feature into the 0.4 release is the approaching release of Node-RED 3.0, now we know that we can be ready to offer our users Node-RED 3.0 as soon as it is released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will also be making available the Beta&#39;s of Node-RED 3.0 within FlowForge Cloud,  this becomes a great way to test out the new features without having to touch your own environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/288&quot;&gt;Story #288 - Change Stacks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/user/changestack/&quot;&gt;Docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;environment-variables&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/04/flowforge-04-released/#environment-variables&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Environment Variables&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another key new feature we are introducing is the ability to set and manage environment variables within your projects.
Environment Variables are a key tool when building applications as they allow you to to separate the configuration of your system from the logic in the code. Even in Low-Code platforms this is an important design pattern. Environment variables are fully integrated into &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/user/concepts/#project-template&quot;&gt;Templates&lt;/a&gt; that we introduced last month so they can be set both at the platform level or on an individual project.
Our plans for the next release will make these even more useful as we introduce the ability to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/271&quot;&gt;duplicate a project&lt;/a&gt; and then modify those variables for the new project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/225&quot;&gt;Story #225 - Project Environment Variables&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/docs/user/envvar/&quot;&gt;Docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;there&#39;s-more&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/04/flowforge-04-released/#there&#39;s-more&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; There&#39;s more&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many more improvements in this release, such as the ability to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/239&quot;&gt;Set the timezone&lt;/a&gt; your project is running in, we&#39;ve also been iterating on our billing experience as we&#39;ve welcomed the first paying customers to FlowForge Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally we&#39;re very happy that we&#39;ve had our first external contribution to the code base, as an Open Core company we believe strongly that Open Source lives at the heart of everything we do.
We would like to say a big thank-you to &lt;a href=&quot;https://fakocodes.netlify.app/&quot;&gt;Fakorede Damilola Idris&lt;/a&gt; for his work on fixing a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/424&quot;&gt;bug&lt;/a&gt; in the UI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-started-with-flowforge&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/04/flowforge-04-released/#getting-started-with-flowforge&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Getting started with FlowForge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The documentation provides a guide for &lt;a href=&quot;http://flowforge.com/docs/install/&quot;&gt;installing FlowForge on a local server&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven&#39;t played with FlowForge yet, here&#39;s a more complete walk-through
of the platform:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YYZDx8n17Ys&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;upgrading-flowforge&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/04/flowforge-04-released/#upgrading-flowforge&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Upgrading FlowForge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you installed a previous version of FlowForge  and want to upgrade, our documentation provides a
guide for &lt;a href=&quot;http://flowforge.com/docs/install#upgrade&quot;&gt;upgrading FlowForge on a local server&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-help&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/04/flowforge-04-released/#getting-help&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Getting help&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you hit any problems with the platform, or have questions to ask, please do
raise an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues&quot;&gt;issue on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That also includes if you have any feedback or feature requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also have a &lt;code&gt;#flowforge&lt;/code&gt; channel on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodered.org/slack&quot;&gt;Node-RED Slack workspace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what&#39;s-next%3F&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/04/flowforge-04-released/#what&#39;s-next%3F&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; What&#39;s next?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our regular release cycle puts the next release on Thursday 12th May.
We will be building on features in the last few releases around managing your projects and using templates, we&#39;re also  setting the foundations of our work to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/446&quot;&gt;manage Node-RED on your own devices running at the Edge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/announcing-flowforge-cloud/&quot;&gt;announcement blog post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also sign up to our general mailing list below if you want to hear more
about the work we&#39;re doing.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/04/flowforge-accepting-customers/</id>
        <title>FlowForge is accepting customers now</title>
        <summary>We&#39;re starting to onboard users from the waitlist</summary>
        <updated>2022-04-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/04/flowforge-accepting-customers/"/>
        <author><name>ZJ van de Weg</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A year ago our CTO, Nick O&#39;Leary, &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2021/04/first-deploy/&quot;&gt;introduced FlowForge&lt;/a&gt;.
Since then major milestones have been achieved. As we grow as a company, important
steps are taken. Today we make another very important step; we&#39;re accepting our
first customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago our product was nearly in a state where it could support customers,
when that was the case, we &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/02/announcing-flowforge-cloud/&quot;&gt;opened up our waitlist&lt;/a&gt;.
The waitlist has been growing daily and now we&#39;re ready to start inviting those
users onto the platform. The first
lucky few users are being added today, and each working day for the foreseeable
future we&#39;ll continue onboarding users. New users will receive an email from our
team with their login details and can start creating new workflows with Node-RED
minutes after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the source code of FlowForge is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge&quot;&gt;available&lt;/a&gt;,
there&#39;s a chance you&#39;re unfamiliar with what has been built around Node-RED.
With FlowForge, our intent is to build a platform to aid with colaboration of
flows in Node-RED. The first steps to our vision include a managed Node-RED
instance to connect virtually any online service. Multiple users will have
access to the same flows and can collaborate. Further, once Node-RED 3.0 has
been released, the platform will provide a pain-free way to upgrade and keep
your projects up to date. There&#39;s many more exciting features right around the
corner on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/orgs/flowforge/projects/5&quot;&gt;roadmap&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/03/flowforge-03-released/</id>
        <title>FlowForge 0.3 released</title>
        <summary>Moving towards the launch of FlowForge Cloud</summary>
        <updated>2022-03-17T01:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/03/flowforge-03-released/"/>
        <author><name>Nick O&#39;Leary</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The FlowForge 0.3 release brings us closer to the launch of FlowForge Cloud.
Find out more about what&#39;s in this new release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release of the FlowForge platform brings some significant new features that
will underpin more of what is to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;project-stacks-%26-templates&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/03/flowforge-03-released/#project-stacks-%26-templates&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Project Stacks &amp;amp; Templates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we think about what a makes a Project inside FlowForge, the simple answer
is Node-RED.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more complete answer is: a version of Node-RED, a version of Node.js, some
memory, some CPU and a bunch of Node-RED settings to customise the instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a platform like FlowForge, it&#39;s important to have the tools to manage all
of these things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where Project Stacks and Template come in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Project Stack defines the underlying characteristics of the Node-RED process -
or the container it is running in. For example, with our Local deployment model,
it defines the version of Node-RED to use and how much memory the process should
try to use. In our container based deployment models, the stack identifies the
container to use for the project, along with memory and CPU limits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a future release, this will be the way we will support upgrading the version
of Node-RED a project is using - and doing so in a well managed way. An Administrator
will be able to create a new Stack containing the new version of Node-RED.
Project owners will then be able to update their projects to use the new Stack -
at a time that is convenient to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Project Template is more about how the Node-RED instance is configured - exposing
the options a user would traditional modify in their Node-RED settings file.
With this release, we&#39;re not exposing a lot of settings as the focus has been
more on the underlying Template concept. But it will be the basis for gradually
exposing more options for customisation in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/285&quot;&gt;Epic #285 - Project Stacks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/141&quot;&gt;Epic #141 - Project Templates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;billing-integration&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/03/flowforge-03-released/#billing-integration&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Billing Integration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With our open core philosophy, the heart of the FlowForge platform is open source
and available under the Apache 2 license for anyone to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the plan was always to have certain features that were licensed separately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release brings the first of those features - Stripe Billing Integration. This
feature brings the ability to require a Team to have a Stripe Billing agreement
in place and to be able to charge on a per-project basis within that Team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being able to charge is an important feature for any commercial platform, and
with our own FlowForge Cloud launching soon, we needed to get this feature in
place today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve structured the code in the repository and updated the LICENSE file to make it
very clear what parts of the code base are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; covered by the Apache 2 license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/224&quot;&gt;Epic #224 - Billing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-started-with-flowforge&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/03/flowforge-03-released/#getting-started-with-flowforge&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Getting started with FlowForge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The documentation provides a guide for &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/tree/main/docs&quot;&gt;installing FlowForge on a local server&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven&#39;t played with FlowForge yet, here&#39;s a more complete walk-through
of the platform:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YYZDx8n17Ys&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;upgrading-flowforge&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/03/flowforge-03-released/#upgrading-flowforge&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Upgrading FlowForge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you installed FlowForge 0.1 or 0.2 and want to upgrade, our documentation provides a
guide for &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/tree/main/docs/install/local#upgrade&quot;&gt;upgrading FlowForge on a local server&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-help&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/03/flowforge-03-released/#getting-help&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Getting help&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you hit any problems with the platform, or have questions to ask, please do
raise an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues&quot;&gt;issue on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That also includes if you have any feedback or feature requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also have a &lt;code&gt;#flowforge&lt;/code&gt; channel on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodered.org/slack&quot;&gt;Node-RED Slack workspace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what&#39;s-next%3F&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/03/flowforge-03-released/#what&#39;s-next%3F&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; What&#39;s next?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our regular release cycle puts the next release on Thursday 14th April.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re still in planning stage for the release, but we&#39;ll also be beginning to invite
people from the waiting list to sign-up to FlowForge Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/announcing-flowforge-cloud/&quot;&gt;annoucement blog post&lt;/a&gt;.
You can also sign up to our general mailing list below if you want to hear more
about the work we&#39;re doing.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/02/announcing-flowforge-cloud/</id>
        <title>Announcing FlowForge Cloud</title>
        <summary>Hosting your Node-RED, so you don&#39;t have to.</summary>
        <updated>2022-02-23T19:44:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/02/announcing-flowforge-cloud/"/>
        <author><name>ZJ van de Weg</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As an open core company, anyone is free to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/tree/9219e81399eaf52fb0ee5573707a52f5520fbfdd/docs/install&quot;&gt;download and install&lt;/a&gt;
our platform. In many cases this is a great solution, it
allows for custom setups in your own environment. We know this isn&#39;t for everyone
though, some people just want to start building with Node-RED without having to manage their servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce FlowForge Cloud, a hosted
Node-RED as a service offering and today we are opening the waitlist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our waitlist captures your email, and we&#39;ll reach out to you on that address once your account is created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;starting-operations&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/02/announcing-flowforge-cloud/#starting-operations&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Starting operations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having released v0.2 recently, we&#39;re now working on v0.3 that will include
a user flow for &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/224&quot;&gt;billing&lt;/a&gt;.
When that work has been done and deployed people on the waitlist will slowly be invited to the platform.
Currently that&#39;s scheduled for April 1st, no joke, although it could happen either sooner
or later.
More details on the exact pricing will be availble nearer the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you are invited you will be able to;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create multiple Node-RED projects hosted on flowforge.cloud,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invite team members to collaborate on those projects,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And many more features will automatically become availble with each new release.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/02/flowforge-02-released/</id>
        <title>FlowForge 0.2 released</title>
        <summary>Keeping the releases flowing of our open platform for Node-RED</summary>
        <updated>2022-02-17T01:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/02/flowforge-02-released/"/>
        <author><name>Nick O&#39;Leary</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Four weeks have passed since our initial release of FlowForge, and we&#39;re happy
to release v0.2 today as we continue moving forward and evolve the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There aren&#39;t lots of headline features in this release to tell you about as a lot
of the work has been on the internals, as well as responding to some of the early
feedback from the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features like improving the test framework, and building a database migration
framework may not sound too exciting to the end user, but they are critical pieces
when build a platform that needs to be stable and easy to upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ve also been doing work to get our own instance of the platform running in the
Cloud - and figuring out how to automate as much of that as possible. Aside
from being a key way to test the platform, it helps validate the work we&#39;re doing
for when others come to run it in that way. It also lays the ground work for our
own cloud service we&#39;ll be sharing more about in the coming days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full change-log for the core of the platform is available &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/blob/v0.2.0/CHANGELOG.md&quot;&gt;on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.
But with a further 15 repositories containing different components, each with its
own change-log, we&#39;re still thinking about how best to share a single view of the
updates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-started-with-flowforge&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/02/flowforge-02-released/#getting-started-with-flowforge&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Getting started with FlowForge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The documentation provides a guide for &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/tree/main/docs&quot;&gt;installing FlowForge on a local server&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven&#39;t played with FlowForge 0.1 yet, here&#39;s a more complete walk-through
of the platform:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YYZDx8n17Ys&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;upgrading-flowforge&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/02/flowforge-02-released/#upgrading-flowforge&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Upgrading FlowForge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you installed FlowForge 0.1 and want to upgrade, our documentation provides a
guide for &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/tree/main/docs/install/local#upgrade&quot;&gt;upgrading FlowForge on a local server&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-help&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/02/flowforge-02-released/#getting-help&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Getting help&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you hit any problems with the platform, or have questions to ask, please do
raise an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues&quot;&gt;issue on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That also includes if you have any feedback or feature requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also have a &lt;code&gt;#flowforge&lt;/code&gt; channel on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodered.org/slack&quot;&gt;Node-RED Slack workspace&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what&#39;s-next%3F&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/02/flowforge-02-released/#what&#39;s-next%3F&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; What&#39;s next?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our regular release cycle puts the next release on Thursday 17th March. We&#39;ve
got some key features planned in this release around &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/141&quot;&gt;Project Templates&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues/285&quot;&gt;Stacks&lt;/a&gt; -
which will underpin how you can customise Node-RED within FlowForge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ll also have some exciting news to share about our own hosted service you&#39;ll
be able to sign-up for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sign up to the mailing list below if you want to hear more about the work we&#39;re
doing.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/02/use-case-solar-afloat/</id>
        <title>Using Node-RED to keep Solar PV afloat</title>
        <summary>How spb sonne used Node-RED with a renewable energy solution</summary>
        <updated>2022-02-09T09:26:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/02/use-case-solar-afloat/"/>
        <author><name>ZJ van de Weg</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/krishnanravichandran/&quot;&gt;Krisnan Ravichandran&lt;/a&gt; works
for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sbp.solar/&quot;&gt;spb sonne&lt;/a&gt;, a engineering consultancy for renewable
energy. Within the company he is part of the engineering effort on the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sbp.de/en/news/goembhal-sbp-sonnes-pioneering-floating-pv-system/&quot;&gt;Gömbhal&lt;/a&gt;
project, creating a floatation device for solar panels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post, he shares his experiences of using Node-RED.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently there’s a prototype deployed in Hungary, while the company is located
in Stuttgart: “We’re remotely monitoring the installation. There are over 40
sensors that all connect to an ADAM-6717, Compact Intelligent Gateway. When the
data is acquired we leverage Node-RED flows that maintain the structure, monitor
performance, and provide reporting back to our offices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Node-RED is embedded in the ADAM 6717, it was very new to me. I was already
experienced in programming, mainly Python, and within a month I felt very
comfortable and productive in Node-RED. Understanding programming is useful,
though not a necessity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building and improving flows I did on my own through trial-and-error, as well
as a lot of times through help on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://discourse.nodered.org/&quot;&gt;Node-RED Forum&lt;/a&gt;.
The community is helpful and welcoming to new users. Now I maintain multiple
flows with very different purposes. Some track temperature,
irradiation wind-speed, direction, tilt and wave height; to ensure the floating
PV installation remains floating. Other sensors are connected to actuators
through flows that control pressure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do have some challenges; the ADAM 6717 contained an older version of Node-RED.
This raised questions around security and maintenance, as our Node-RED version
isn’t updated to a newer version in an easy manner. It also hampers training a
bit because documentation might reference an API or node for a flow that’s just
not the same on older versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I’d choose Node-RED again, it’s well known as well as easy to learn.
Furthermore I found it very versatile.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Krisnan for sharing his story. If you have a Node-RED story for us
to share, please get in touch via &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:contact@flowforge.com&quot;&gt;contact@flowforge.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/02/welcome-joe/</id>
        <title>Welcome Joe</title>
        <summary></summary>
        <updated>2022-02-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/02/welcome-joe/"/>
        <author><name>Nick O&#39;Leary</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today we welcome Joe Pavitt (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/joepavitt3d&quot;&gt;@joepavitt3d&lt;/a&gt;) as
our new Head of UX &amp;amp; Design. This is a key role that will help deliver the awesome
user experience of the FlowForge platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joe has a passion for user experience, data visualisation and creativity in
technology. He joins us having been at IBM for 9 years where he specialised in
building bespoke, first of a kind experiences in IBM&#39;s Emerging Technology and
Research teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We worked together at IBM and I saw first-hand the range and quality of what he
can do. I was super pleased when he agreed to join us and I look forward to
seeing the real impact he&#39;ll have on what we&#39;re building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome aboard Joe!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/01/flowforge-01-released/</id>
        <title>FlowForge 0.1 released</title>
        <summary>Making the first release of the platform and transitioning to open development</summary>
        <updated>2022-01-20T01:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/01/flowforge-01-released/"/>
        <author><name>Nick O&#39;Leary</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For an open core company, we haven&#39;t been very open with what we&#39;re doing. That all
changes today with the release of FlowForge 0.1 and making all of our repositories
public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a significant step for the company as we look to build a platform around Node-RED.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main question we get asked is: &#39;What is FlowForge?&amp;quot; - which is a very reasonable
question to ask.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FlowForge is a platform for managing Node-RED instances at scale. It lets you have
multiple users on the platform, organised into teams to provide proper access control
to individual Node-RED instances, or Projects as we call them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the 0.1 release, we have the basic building blocks of the platform in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add multiple users to the platform&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create teams for those users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create Node-RED projects quickly and easily through the platform UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a more complete walk-through of the platform in this early release, you can
watch this video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YYZDx8n17Ys&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-started-with-flowforge&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/01/flowforge-01-released/#getting-started-with-flowforge&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Getting started with FlowForge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The documentation provides a guide for &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/tree/main/docs&quot;&gt;installing FlowForge on a local server&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also have drivers for deploying to Docker Compose and Kubernetes based environments
to enable a larger scale of deployment. We&#39;ll have more documentation on those options
in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-help&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/01/flowforge-01-released/#getting-help&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Getting help&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you hit any problems with the platform, or have questions to ask, please do
raise an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/flowforge/flowforge/issues&quot;&gt;issue on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That also includes if you have any feedback or feature requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what&#39;s-next%3F&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/01/flowforge-01-released/#what&#39;s-next%3F&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; What&#39;s next?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With so much in the plan and lots of exciting features to come, we will have a
regular cycle of releases every four weeks. So you can expect the next release, 0.2,
on Thursday 17th February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we&#39;re only at 0.1 today, there is a lot still to do. We will be following the
principles of &lt;a href=&quot;https://semver.org/&quot;&gt;Semantic Versioning&lt;/a&gt; with our releases,
but until we reach 1.0, there may be some disruptive changes along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sign up to the mailing list below if you want to hear more about the work we&#39;re
doing.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/01/welcome-steve/</id>
        <title>Welcome Steve</title>
        <summary></summary>
        <updated>2022-01-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/01/welcome-steve/"/>
        <author><name>Nick O&#39;Leary</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We&#39;re continuing to grow the FlowForge team with our latest hire; Steve McLaughlin
who is joining our development team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve is a well known face in the Node-RED community. He is a regular contributor
to the community forum, always happy to help users with their questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has published a number of very popular nodes, include &lt;a href=&quot;https://flows.nodered.org/node/node-red-contrib-buffer-parser&quot;&gt;buffer-parser&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&quot;https://flows.nodered.org/node/node-red-contrib-cron-plus&quot;&gt;cron-plus&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;https://flows.nodered.org/node/node-red-contrib-image-tools&quot;&gt;image-tools&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has also made some significant contributions to the core of Node-RED, such as
delivering MQTTv5 support and introducing the Monaco code editor into the heart
of the editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve joins us from a background in Industrial IoT in the automative manufacturing
space - experience and knowledge that will be invaluable as we look to growing the
FlowForge platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve will be focussed on the Node-RED side of our activities - helping to continue
the ongoing development and growth of the open source project at the heart of what
FlowForge is about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome aboard Steve!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/01/welcome-zj/</id>
        <title>Welcome ZJ</title>
        <summary></summary>
        <updated>2022-01-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2022/01/welcome-zj/"/>
        <author><name>Nick O&#39;Leary</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This year the FlowForge team will grow further, and I&#39;m excited to announce our
newest addition to the team; Zeger-Jan van de Weg (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ZJvandeWeg&quot;&gt;@ZJvandeWeg&lt;/a&gt;).
Zeger-Jan, also known as ZJ, is joining FlowForge as CEO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ZJ previously worked at GitLab where he helped build a vibrant open source
community and we&#39;re thrilled to have him to continue this with the Node-RED
community. Under his supervision the involvement of GitLab in the Git project
grew significantly, allowing Git and GitLab to be successful together. This aligns
well with our vision for FlowForge:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will only be successful if the whole Node-RED community is successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As our first non-engineering hire, ZJ will be focussed on growing the business side
of FlowForge, working on marketing and ongoing business development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome aboard ZJ!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2021/05/welcome-sam/</id>
        <title>Welcome Sam</title>
        <summary></summary>
        <updated>2021-05-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2021/05/welcome-sam/"/>
        <author><name>Nick O&#39;Leary</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the things I&#39;m most looking forward to with starting FlowForge is building
the team who are going to help create something special and have fun whilst doing it.
With Ben having joined last week, this week I get to share the news that Sam Machin (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sammachin&quot;&gt;@sammachin&lt;/a&gt;) is joining the team as a Senior Developer Advocate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sam is a seasoned Developer Advocate, who really understands the difference
between evangelism and advocacy. He is acutely aware of the differences between
developers as customers and as partners in an ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Node-RED community is so important to us - we simply wouldn&#39;t be doing what
we do today without their support. As we continue to drive the project forward,
and build the FlowForge platform around it, we have to keep developers are the heart
of what we do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping that 2-way conversation open is not an easy task, but Sam&#39;s in a great
position to help us do just that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sam is an experienced Product Manager and will be able to give the community a seat at the table when it comes to shaping our plans. The Node-RED community is an integral part of what will make FlowForge a success and his first responsibility is to ensure that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome aboard Sam!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2021/05/welcome-ben/</id>
        <title>Welcome Ben</title>
        <summary></summary>
        <updated>2021-05-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2021/05/welcome-ben/"/>
        <author><name>Nick O&#39;Leary</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m excited to share the news that Ben Hardill (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hardillb&quot;&gt;@hardillb&lt;/a&gt;) is joining FlowForge as a Senior Engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve known Ben for many years, having worked together at IBM. He&#39;s been an active member
of the Node-RED community since the start of the project and he published one of
the very first &lt;a href=&quot;https://flows.nodered.org/node/node-red-node-geofence&quot;&gt;3rd party nodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is ever-present on Stack Overflow, to the point where I&#39;ve long since stopped
rushing to respond to questions tagged with &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/node-red&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;node-red&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
in the full knowledge that he has usually beaten me to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More recently he&#39;s been doing some really interesting work exploring &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hardill.me.uk/wordpress/2020/10/01/multi-tenant-node-red/&quot;&gt;multi-tenant Node-RED systems&lt;/a&gt; - something we&#39;ll
be continuing at FlowForge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome aboard Ben!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/2021/04/first-deploy/</id>
        <title>Introducing FlowForge Inc.</title>
        <summary>Building a new low-code development platform around the Node-RED project</summary>
        <updated>2021-04-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/2021/04/first-deploy/"/>
        <author><name>Nick O&#39;Leary</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When Dave and I first created &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodered.org/&quot;&gt;Node-RED&lt;/a&gt;, it was a tool to solve a
problem - allowing us to do our day job more effectively when building IoT solutions
for clients. That gave us the means and purpose to create a truly useful platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it became an open source project, it quickly found an enthusiastic audience that
has seen the community grow beyond our imagination. From both individual users, to a wide
range of companies integrating it into their own products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But with that growth, the question in my mind has always been how to take it further
and secure its long term future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodered.org/blog/2020/10/13/future-plans&quot;&gt;project blog&lt;/a&gt;
last year about the future plans of the project. A key piece of that is its sustainability -
how we can increase the commercial adoption of Node-RED and how we can get more people
contributing back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An opportunity presented itself earlier this year that I believe will bring a
step-change to what the Node-RED project is able to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;introducing-flowforge-inc.&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2021/04/first-deploy/#introducing-flowforge-inc.&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Introducing FlowForge Inc.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So today, I&#39;m launching FlowForge Inc - a new company whose mission is to build a low-coding development
platform fit for the enterprise with Node-RED at its heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Backed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/sijbrandij/&quot;&gt;Sid Sijbrandij&lt;/a&gt;, we have funding
in place to create a fully remote team dedicated to an open core model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the short term, this means helping to accelerate the plans already in place for
the Open Source project. Getting the 2.0 release done in the next few weeks, working on
long-standing features such as the Test framework and Flow Debugger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alongside that we&#39;ll also be building a platform around Node-RED that will make it easier
to adopt at scale and integrate into existing enterprise environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Node-RED remains a fully open source project, with its home at the OpenJS Foundation
and an open governance model that allows anyone to have a say in its development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our goal is to incorporate as much of our work directly into the core project as possible. Where we do create closed-source components, we will work with the community to ensure the right APIs and extension points are in the core for all to benefit from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will only be successful if the whole Node-RED community is successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me personally, this is a really exciting next step. I never expected to turn my little side project into a full-time job and now into a company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;hiring-soon!&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/2021/04/first-deploy/#hiring-soon!&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Hiring soon!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ll be hiring soon - so keep an eye out if you&#39;re interesting in getting involved.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
</feed>