<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>FlowForge</title>
    <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self"/>
    <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog"/>
    <updated>2022-01-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://flowforge.com/blog</id>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/welcome-zj/</id>
        <title>Welcome ZJ</title>
        <summary></summary>
        <updated>2022-01-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/welcome-zj/"/>
        <author><name>Nick O&#39;Leary</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This year the FlowForge team will grow further, and I&#39;m excited to announce our
newest addition to the team; Zeger-Jan van de Weg (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ZJvandeWeg&quot;&gt;@ZJvandeWeg&lt;/a&gt;).
Zeger-Jan, also known as ZJ, is joining FlowForge as CEO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ZJ previously worked at GitLab where he helped build a vibrant open source
community and we&#39;re thrilled to have him to continue this with the Node-RED
community. Under his supervision the involvement of GitLab in the Git project
grew significantly, allowing Git and GitLab to be successful together. This aligns
well with our vision for FlowForge:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will only be successful if the whole Node-RED community is successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As our first non-engineering hire, ZJ will be focussed on growing the business side
of FlowForge, working on marketing and ongoing business development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome aboard ZJ!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/welcome-sam/</id>
        <title>Welcome Sam</title>
        <summary></summary>
        <updated>2021-05-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/welcome-sam/"/>
        <author><name>Nick O&#39;Leary</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the things I&#39;m most looking forward to with starting FlowForge is building
the team who are going to help create something special and have fun whilst doing it.
With Ben having joined last week, this week I get to share the news that Sam Machin (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sammachin&quot;&gt;@sammachin&lt;/a&gt;) is joining the team as a Senior Developer Advocate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sam is a seasoned Developer Advocate, who really understands the difference
between evangelism and advocacy. He is acutely aware of the differences between
developers as customers and as partners in an ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Node-RED community is so important to us - we simply wouldn&#39;t be doing what
we do today without their support. As we continue to drive the project forward,
and build the FlowForge platform around it, we have to keep developers are the heart
of what we do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping that 2-way conversation open is not an easy task, but Sam&#39;s in a great
position to help us do just that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sam is an experienced Product Manager and will be able to give the community a seat at the table when it comes to shaping our plans. The Node-RED community is an integral part of what will make FlowForge a success and his first responsibility is to ensure that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome aboard Sam!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/welcome-ben/</id>
        <title>Welcome Ben</title>
        <summary></summary>
        <updated>2021-05-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/welcome-ben/"/>
        <author><name>Nick O&#39;Leary</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m excited to share the news that Ben Hardill (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/hardillb&quot;&gt;@hardillb&lt;/a&gt;) is joining FlowForge as a Senior Engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve known Ben for many years, having worked together at IBM. He&#39;s been an active member
of the Node-RED community since the start of the project and he published one of
the very first &lt;a href=&quot;https://flows.nodered.org/node/node-red-node-geofence&quot;&gt;3rd party nodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is ever-present on Stack Overflow, to the point where I&#39;ve long since stopped
rushing to respond to questions tagged with &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/node-red&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;node-red&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
in the full knowledge that he has usually beaten me to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More recently he&#39;s been doing some really interesting work exploring &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hardill.me.uk/wordpress/2020/10/01/multi-tenant-node-red/&quot;&gt;multi-tenant Node-RED systems&lt;/a&gt; - something we&#39;ll
be continuing at FlowForge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome aboard Ben!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    
    <entry>
        <id>https://flowforge.com/blog/first-deploy/</id>
        <title>Introducing FlowForge Inc.</title>
        <summary>Building a new low-code development platform around the Node-RED project</summary>
        <updated>2021-04-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
        <link href="https://flowforge.com/blog/first-deploy/"/>
        <author><name>Nick O&#39;Leary</name></author>
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When Dave and I first created &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodered.org/&quot;&gt;Node-RED&lt;/a&gt;, it was a tool to solve a
problem - allowing us to do our day job more effectively when building IoT solutions
for clients. That gave us the means and purpose to create a truly useful platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it became an open source project, it quickly found an enthusiastic audience that
has seen the community grow beyond our imagination. From both individual users, to a wide
range of companies integrating it into their own products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But with that growth, the question in my mind has always been how to take it further
and secure its long term future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nodered.org/blog/2020/10/13/future-plans&quot;&gt;project blog&lt;/a&gt;
last year about the future plans of the project. A key piece of that is its sustainability -
how we can increase the commercial adoption of Node-RED and how we can get more people
contributing back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An opportunity presented itself earlier this year that I believe will bring a
step-change to what the Node-RED project is able to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;introducing-flowforge-inc.&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/first-deploy/#introducing-flowforge-inc.&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Introducing FlowForge Inc.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So today, I&#39;m launching FlowForge Inc - a new company whose mission is to build a low-coding development
platform fit for the enterprise with Node-RED at its heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Backed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/sijbrandij/&quot;&gt;Sid Sijbrandij&lt;/a&gt;, we have funding
in place to create a fully remote team dedicated to an open core model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the short term, this means helping to accelerate the plans already in place for
the Open Source project. Getting the 2.0 release done in the next few weeks, working on
long-standing features such as the Test framework and Flow Debugger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alongside that we&#39;ll also be building a platform around Node-RED that will make it easier
to adopt at scale and integrate into existing enterprise environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Node-RED remains a fully open source project, with its home at the OpenJS Foundation
and an open governance model that allows anyone to have a say in its development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our goal is to incorporate as much of our work directly into the core project as possible. Where we do create closed-source components, we will work with the community to ensure the right APIs and extension points are in the core for all to benefit from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will only be successful if the whole Node-RED community is successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me personally, this is a really exciting next step. I never expected to turn my little side project into a full-time job and now into a company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;hiring-soon!&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;header-anchor&quot; href=&quot;https://flowforge.com/blog/first-deploy/#hiring-soon!&quot;&gt;#&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt; Hiring soon!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#39;ll be hiring soon - so keep an eye out if you&#39;re interesting in getting involved.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
</feed>